<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tales of Murder</title>
    <description>For readers with time to kill!</description>
    <link>http://talesofmurder.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://talesofmurder.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 09:45:46 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 09:45:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 04:13:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://talesofmurder.com/jekyll/update/2014/07/11/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://talesofmurder.com/jekyll/update/2014/07/11/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Man Who Would Not Die</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A WOMAN, young, handsome, richly dressed, lay dead on the sidewalk. Over her stood a young man, hatless, his hair mussed, his face bruised and bleeding. Around them–the living and the dead–the crowd surged, held back by a little cordon of blue-coated policemen. A police automobile, its gong clanging raucously, dashed up to the curb and a tall, broad-shouldered man in plain clothes leaped out and elbowed his way through the throng of curiosity seekers to the sergeant in charge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Great Heavens, Casey!” he exclaimed, as his glance fell upon the face of the woman. “Do you know who she is?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey touched his cap respectfully. “Tins chap here says that she’s Mrs. Augustus Winters, the young wife that old Winters, the millionaire, married a couple of years ago. Used to be an actress before she married him, I understand. I don’t know the lady myself, inspector.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big man nodded. “He’s right, Casey. It’s Mrs. Winters all right.” He caught himself with a start. “No, by George, it isn’t!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bareheaded young man with the bruised face interrupted. “You are wrong, sir. I know that it is Mrs. Winters.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector gave him a quick look. “You mean that you think it is she. The fact of the matter is that Mrs. Winters died suddenly yesterday afternoon.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You must be wrong,” argued the other stubbornly. “I have waited on Mrs. Winters hundreds of times. I know her as well as I know myself. And she was alive and well ten minutes ago.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Couldn’t you be mistaken? I’ll admit that this woman looks enough like her to be her double. Must be her sister.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I insist that you are wrong, sir. I’ll take my oath that this is Mrs. Winters lying there.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Des Moines scratched his chin reflectively. “It’s got me beat!” he declared. “There’s only one thing to do, under the circumstances, Casey–get the body to the morgue and send for old Winters to identify it. Ask him if his wife was a twin. And,” turning to the young man, “you get your hat and come on with me to the station. I want to have a talk with you.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seated at the big, flat-top desk in his well appointed office, Des Moines lighted a cigar in silence, offered another to his companion, then suddenly demanded : &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, come clean, young fellow. What’s the story behind this affair? Let’s have the straight of it.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lad–he was scarcely more than a boy–gulped to hide his agitation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I–I–” he stammered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector smiled kindly. “Don’t get scared, my boy. Don’t get scared. Bless your heart, sonny, I know that you didn’t kill the woman. I Only want to get at the facts in the case as speedily as possible. Just forget my gruff way of speaking–it’s my natural voice.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hardly know how to start,” began the other, his fears vanishing under the inspector’s kindly manner. “The lady–Mrs. Winters^-came into Harden &amp;amp; Company’s store, where I am employed as head salesman in the jewelry department, and asked to be shown something rather ‘nifty’ in a diamond brooch. That was yesterday afternoon. She looked at a number of pieces, finally selecting one valued at thirty thousand dollars. She asked me to lay it aside for her, stating that she wanted her mother, who was buying it for her for a birthday present, to look at it before she made her final decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This morning she returned and, coming into the store, requested that I accompany her to the curb with the brooch, as her mother, who was an invalid, was outside in the limousine. Of course it was irregular, but she is an old customer–you know Harden &amp;amp; Company’s policy–so I did as requested. I handed her the jewel case just as we reached the machine and she passed it in to the woman–whom I supposed was her mother–who was leaning back against the cushions. The curtains were down and the interior was in semi-darkness, so I did not get a clear view of the face of the lady. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just as she handed the other the jewel, the chauffeur, who had been keeping his engine running, leaned out and slugged me with something–a sandbag, I imagine. At the same time Mrs. Winters made a quick leap for the interior of the machine. But, involuntarily, as I fell I grasped her, and we went down in a heap together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘The chauffeur immediately started his machine and, before I recovered my wits, which had been largely knocked out of me, he was around the corner. I didn’t even have an opportunity to get the number of the auto.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have already attended to that,” interrupted the inspector. “Casey’ll have it down in his notebook if anyone in the vicinity chanced to notice it. Were there many people on the sidewalk at the time?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They were constantly passing–the usual ten o’clock crowd.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Um-m-m. All right, go ahead with your story.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is nothing more to tell. When I came to my senses–and I couldn’t have been dazed more than a second or two–the machine was disappearing around the corner, as I just told you, and the woman was lying on the sidewalk beside me–dead. It must have-been apoplexy, inspector, for I’ll swear on a stack of Bibles that I didn’t seize her hard enough to kill her.” He hesitated, then continued, haltingly: “But what puzzles me is why Mrs. Winters–a woman of untold wealth– would stoop to aid in a crime like that.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at the inspector for an answer to his question. The latter smoked in silence for a second. “That’s what we’ve got to find out, my boy. You said your name was–” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Johnson–Adolph Johnson.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, yes. And she got away clean with the jewelry did she? The other woman–the one in the machine–and the chauffeur?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnson nodded. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were interrupted by a rap at the door. In response to Des Moines” gruff “Come in!” Casey entered, his good-natured, red face glowing with excitement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the dickens do you know about it, sir?” he exploded. “Winters has identified the body, positively, as being that of his wife.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But Mrs. Winters died yesterday afternoon.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She did. But sometime during the night her body disappeared. And this morning they found the body of her maid, dead, in the casket from which the mistress had been taken t” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good God I Murdered?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not a mark on her body.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;III &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the inspector could recover from his astonishment, the door burst open and a man, grey-haired, tall, angular–beyond the middle age–rushed in without the formality of rapping. His wrinkled face was drawn and haggard, his eyes bloodshot and red from weeping, his whole appearance that of a man almost bereft of his senses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Inspector,” he shrieked, “who is the guilty man? Who has desecrated the poor, dead body of my wife? Who stole it from the casket ? Damn them! Damn them I Damn them! Who murdered Dolly, her maid ? She was murdered, I say! I know it! I know it!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He glared about him for a second. Then: “Give him to me, I say! I’ll tear the scoundrel to pieces with my naked hands! Give him to me! I demand justice!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He dropped into a chair and burst into hysterical sobs. For an instant there was silence. Des Moines chewed thoughtfully on his cigar. Johnson, white-faced, unused to scenes such as this, fidgeted nervously, his fingers twitching. Assuming the quieting tone of a mother addressing her child, the inspector turned to the weeping man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Calm yourself, Mr. Winters,” he began, slowly. “I know that it’s hard– it’s awful, terrible. But we’ll get at the bottom of it some way. I promise you on my word as a man that I’ll capture the guilty wretch and hang him. Yes, curse him! I’ll hang him higher than a kite, or I’ll quit the force! But the affair is growing more puzzling every minute. I can’t make head nor tail out of it as it stands now. Won’t you let me hear your &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winters sat up and dried his eyes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What can I tell you?” he sobbed. “How shall I begin?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Start with the death of your wife.” “There is little to tell. She was stricken, suddenly, yesterday afternoon while dressing to go out. Dolly Matthews, her maid, who was with her at the time, hastily summoned assistance. But she passed away before the doctor arrived–in fact, even before the servants, who responded to Miss Matthews’ cries, could reach her. The physician–Doctor Bennett, the well-known specialist–gave as his opinion that the cause of death was heart failure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The body was prepared for burial in the usual way. I sat beside the casket until nearly morning. Then, in response to the urgent appeals of the friends and relatives who had rushed to my side in my hour of trouble, I surrendered my post to Miss Matthews. The poor girl loved my wife devotedly and was terribly grief stricken over her untimely death. And now she’s gone, too!” He burst into another paroxysm of sobbing. Des Moines waited until he regained control of himself, then motioned for him to continue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I could not content myself. My nerves were nearly at the breaking point, although the physician had given me an opiate to quiet me. After lying on the bed and tossing around for an hour or two, I arose and again sought the side of my dear one. I was surprised not to find Miss Matthews in the room, which was empty, although there, were several people in the study just across the hall. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”/ stepped to the casket. As there is a Cod in Heaven, the body of my wife was gone! In its place was the body of Dolly, her maid, cold in death!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was no evidence of foul play in the case of the maid ?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, although I am. certain, under the circumstances, that she was murdered. She couldn’t have died a natural death and crawled into the casket herself, could she?” He glared at the inspector as if expecting a denial. Receiving no answer he continued: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My cries brought those who were in the other room and we immediately summoned Doctor Bennett, who made an examination. He would not even venture an opinion as to what caused death. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Meanwhile, I was almost beside myself. Can you blame me? We searched the house from cellar to garret, looking for the remains of my wife. Failing to find her body, we were about to call up police headquarters–which we should have done in the beginning;–when I received the call to go Jo the morgue. There I found the poor dear. I demand that immediate steps be taken to bring the perpetrator of the hellish deed to justice! I am a wealthy man. I will spend every cent I possess to hang the wretch. Damn him!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Des Moines scratched his chin reflectively. “It’s got me beat, Mr. Winters. I’ll confess that I never came across a case like this in all of my twenty years on the force. You are ready to swear that your wife died yesterday afternoon and that you saw her body in the coffin. A reputable physician made an examination and pronounced her dead. Yet– Are you sure that the body you examined in the morgue is that of Mrs. Winters ?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Positively. I identified it, not only by her sweet girlish face, but by a small birthmark on her left shoulder.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She had no sister? She was not a twin?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She was an only child.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then, Mr. Winters, how do you reconcile your story with that of Mr. Johnson, here, who swears that the woman whose body you saw in the morgue, and have identified as your wife, was alive and well at ten o’clock this morning? Yes, he even goes farther and asserts that he talked to her and that she, aided by two others, robbed Harden &amp;amp; Company of a valuable diamond brooch.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winters leaped to Ins feet, his eyes blazing, his face aflame with rage. “He’s an infernal liar and a blackguard–” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before he could continue, there was a rap at the door. Des Moines’ secretary entered. He handed the inspector an envelope marked “Important. Winters Case.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policeman tore the envelope open and glanced hastily over the contents. Then, with an oath, he read it aloud to the others: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dear Inspector: I have just started. I am Lessman, the man who laughs at death! I killed Mrs. Winters! I killed her as I have killed others–and as I will kill again–by the power of thought alone! Unravel that if you can. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is death, my dear inspectors? Who knows? No one but me. What is the human body? Only a prison in which the soul is confined–a piece of clay to be discarded at will. God kills when fie wishes. Why not I? It suited my purpose to use the mortal form of Mrs. Winters, and I took it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hereafter, I will give you due and timely notice of each crime I com mil– and I assure you that they will be numerous. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With best wishes, I sign myself LESSMAN, The Man Who Will Not Die. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IV &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Winters’ mystery was the most interesting news event of the day and the afternoon papers made the most of it. At its best, the city administration was not a favorite with the press. Augustus Winters was wealthy and popular, his wife had been one of the leaders of the faster young society set. As a result, the police department was grilled to a turnover for what was termed the laxity of its methods. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Des Moines, accustomed to the vagaries of journalism, used to being praised one day and reviled the next, gave little heed to what was said or written about him or his department. Yet he read every detail carefully in the hope that the reporters had gathered some new evidence that would tend to help in working out the solution of the puzzle. For in the past he had secured much valuable help from the newspapermen. But this time he was doomed to disappointment. They could find nothing– absolutely nothing–‘that gave him any additional light. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing had been left undone. Men from the inspector’s office had combed the city in search of a clew to the mysterious Lessman. But without avail. Only the machine used in the Harden &amp;amp; Company robbery had been found. Stolen earlier in the day from a garage in the outskirts of the city, it had been abandoned by the side of a country road when the users were through with it. Beyond that one small detail, no headway had been made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newspapers had assigned their best man to the case. They could secure not even a trace of the unknown perpetrator of the startling crimes–for Des Moines had not thought it advisable to take the press into his confidence in so far as the threatening letter he had received was concerned. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tired and disgruntled, he was about to leave the office, for the night, when the ‘phone on his desk thrilled. He picked the receiver from its hook and answered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Inspector Des Moines?” queried a heavy, male voice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines answered in the affirmative. The man at the other end of the line chuckled to himself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well?” growled the Inspector. “Did you call me to the ‘phone at this time of the night to tell me a joke?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instantly, the quiet laughter ceased and the voice came clear and strong across the space. “No, inspector, I beg your pardon. This is Lessman speaking !–Lessman, the Man Who Will Not Die! I imagined that I would catch you in your office. I had a notion to call around and see you, then thought better of it. Can you understand me all right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, listen to me carefully, Des Moines. I told you that I would give you fair warning when I was ready to make my next move. I always keep my word. Are you listening? Tomorrow morning, on the stroke of ten, I am going to kill a man! Where? Oh, no, T have no objection to telling you where– on the street in front of 1416 Broadway–yes, 1416 Broadway! Probably a policeman ! No. no, not you. But be on the job, inspector. I am doing this for a purpose. I hate the police, damn them! But it will give you an opportunity of studying my methods. Ha, ha! You and I will match wits frequently from now on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, yes. Before I say good night I’ll make you a promise. If you’ll be present tomorrow, I’ll promise you that I will do my best to hunt you up and talk with you. You need not go to the trouble of notifying the papers, for I have done that myself. I’ve asked them all to send their best men. That’s all for this time. Good-bye!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The receiver at the other end was hung up with a click. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Des Moines was galvanized into action. Frantically, he jiggled the hook up and down until Central answered sharply. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Quick!” he demanded. “This is Inspector Des Moines at Headquarters. Where did that call come from just now ? Get on the job and find out. Fifty dollars in it for you if you’ll find out immediately!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hold the line, please!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty seconds later his vigilance was rewarded. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the Chief Operator. The call you inquired about came from booth number fourteen at the Biltmore. Send the reward to Operator One-hundred-and-Six, please.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To secure a connection with the switchboard operator at the Biltmore required only an instant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Inspector Des Moines, Headquarters, speaking. A man just called me up from booth number fourteen. There’s a ten in it for you if you’ll get a description of him for me inside of a minute. Do you understand ? Move fast!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can send the ten right along, inspector. The man who used booth number fourteen stopped at the desk and gave me a tip as he passed out. He just went through the door a second ago.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fine! Fine! His description? Quick!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know him, inspector. It was Augustus Winters, the millionaire!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;V &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Des Moines was a man of action. While even his best friends did not claim for him the brilliancy of a Sherlock Holmes, a Cleek of The Forty Faces, an Arsène Lupin, of any of the other celebrated sleuths of fiction, yet, once given (he slender thread of a clew, he followed it to the end. The taunting telephone call led him to believe that, in Augustus Winters, he had the master mind who was directing the crimes in the millionaire’s own household. Why Winters would make way with his wife and her maid–for the detective was firmly of the belief that both women had been murdered–he did not attempt to reason out. He only knew that a crime had been committed and that he, as an officer of the law, was pledged to find the murderer, regardless of who he might be. Just now all straws pointed to Augustus Winters himself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He believed that Winters had overlooked a point in telephoning from a public booth in a hotel where he was so well known; that he was likely to recall his indiscretion and, in an effort to retrieve his lost ground, hasten home in order to provide himself with an alibi, the officer believed, would be his next move. Consequently, to checkmate that alibi and prove it false from its very inception was the obvious thing to do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He reached for the telephone again and called the number of the millionaire’s residence. Not over three or four minutes had elapsed since Winters– or Lessman, as the inspector believed him to be–had talked to him from the Biltmore. To drive from the hotel to his home would take the better part of an hour, even with a fast car. It would take nearly as long to go from Headquarters. And there was always the danger of an accident. Des Moines thought rapidly, then made his decision. The telephone was faster and better than making the trip in person and standing the possible chance of having the aged criminal–and the inspector now had no doubts on that score–reach there first. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sleepy voice answered his ring. “Augustus Winters’ residence,” it said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who is this?” he demanded. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wilkins, the butler, sir.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Has Mr. Winters returned yet?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He has not been out, sir.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let me talk to him then.” Des Moines chuckled softly to himself as he made the demand. He knew that there was no possibility of the millionaire replying. And the testimony of Wilkins would support his charges when the time came to prove the falsity of the alibi. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll connect you with his room, sir,” answered the butler. A second later the inspector was astonished to hear the clear, calm voice of Winters at the other end of the wire. It nearly floored him. He was almost too nonplussed to reply. For Winters, obviously, could not be in two places at once. If this was Winters, then the man who had called him up from the Biltmore must, necessarily, be an impostor. And what manner of man was he who could disguise himself so cleverly that even those who were personally acquainted with the millionaire mistook the counterfeit for the real ? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Des Moines speaking. When did you get back ?” he asked casually, making an effort to hide the agitation that he felt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When did I get back? I was not aware that I had been away!” answered the other testily. “What was it you wanted, inspector? Must be something important to call up at two o’clock in the morning. Have you secured some new information? Or, possibly you have the guilty wretch under arrest ?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines knew that he was defeated. The least he could do was back out gracefully. It was not necessary to divulge his suspicions. He informed Winters as casually as he was able of the telephone message he had received from “The Man Who Would Not Die,” reserving, however, the information that the other had been masquerading as Winters. Then, he abruptly hung up the phone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case was growing more puzzling every minute. Instead of the telephone call clearing up the mystery, he was forced to confess to himself that it only made it darker. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VI &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who was Lessman, the man who termed himself “The Man Who Would Not Die”? Was there such a person, or was it an alias ? Des Moines, humped up in his chair, chewing his dry cigar, went over the case detail by detail. Figuratively speaking, he held it up to the light and dissected it bit-by-bit, piece-by-piece. And, when he had completed the process, he was obliged In confess himself as much in the dark as ever. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who was Lessman? Who was the man of iron nerve and diabolical cunning? Could it be Winters? The inspector had been inclined to suspect the aged moneybags–was still disposed to do so–but what was his motive? Was he insane? Had he the ability–and the nerve–to carry out such a plot? And there, too, was his alibi, cast-iron, puncture proof. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Winters was not Lessman, who was? Could it be Doctor Bennett? The physician admittedly had more opportunity to commit the murders than any one else. But, in his case, too, there was lacking the motive. Could young Johnson, the diamond salesman, be the man? In his case there was a motive–the theft of the brooch. But, on the other hand, there was nothing to show that he had ever visited the Winters home under any pretext. And it was natural to suppose that the person who could cause the death of both the mistress and the maid must have had, sometime at least, entree to the millionaire’s residence. Des Moines had had both the physician, and the salesman investigated. The reports of his men, lying on the desk before him, showed nothing against them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who had spirited the body of Mrs. Winters from its casket? How could she, a dead woman, be alive? And Johnson, as well as other employees of Harden &amp;amp; Company, swore that she had been? They had seen her–talked with her–nearly twenty-four hours after her reported death. How had the body of the maid been placed in the casket the mistress had occupied? Who was the disguised man who had so cleverly passed himself off on the employees of the Biltmore as Augustus Winters?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not until dawn was breaking that Des Moines gave up wrestling with the problem. And when, at last. tired and stiff from his long vigil, he arose and stretched himself, he was forced to admit that he knew no more than when he had first been called into the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was nothing to do but wait. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VII &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human nature is peculiar. A circus always advertises a thriller as its chief attraction; people attend in the hope of seeing the performer make the one little miscalculation that will end fatally. The newspapers had heralded the announcement sent them by Less-man in huge type. Their front pages shrieked forth in colored ink and huge type the news that at ten o’clock the mysterious man who in his letter confessed to the murder of Mrs. Winters and her maid would take another life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For miles people came for the purpose of enjoying what promised to be a thrilling spectacle. A score of policemen attempted to stem the tide, but without success. Around 1416 Broadway, the street was packed for blocks in either direction. Even the reserves were called into action. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In front of 1416 a knot of policemen, headed by Inspector Des Moines in person, waited stolidly, silently, in a suppressed fever o f excitement, like soldiers waiting the signal for an attack. About them the crowd surged and stormed. But bent upon keeping the fiend from carrying out his threat, Des Moines had cleared the street for a space of nearly a hundred feet, holding the curiosity seekers back with his cordon of bluecoats. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of automobiles were caught in the vortex of humanity, their drivers unable to either go forward or to” back out. The officers were forced to let well enough alone; to handle the jam was a task beyond the power of the guardians of the law. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of the machines Des Moines recognized the pale, haggard face of Augustus Winters. The millionaire, huddled up in the back seat, his every movement showing the mental strain under which he was laboring, caught the inspector’s eye and beckoned, Des Moines shouldered his way through the mass of humanity to the side of his automobile. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been caught in the crowd, inspector, and we’re unable to get out. Can’t you help us? You can understand the awful agony that I am suffering at such a time.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines shook his head. “Don’t you realize, Mr. Winters, that if it were humanly possible, I’d have this street cleared and keep it cleared? My men. are working in from the outside– but it’ll be a job of hours, I’m afraid.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But, my God, man! You are not going to allow this murder to take place, are you?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines shrugged his shoulders. “Out of the hundreds of thousands of people packed in this vicinity, Mr. Winters, show me how to pick out the one man–the man I want. My hands are tied. There is nothing for me to do. I must bide my time and wait for the fiend to strike.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, the aged millionaire clutched the other’s shoulder. His eyes dilated. ‘ He leaned forward, his muscles twitching, his face ashen and drawn. “Oh, God!” he shrieked, “It’s happening! Look! Look!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His long, skinny forefinger pointed far out over the heads of the crowd. And then he fell in a heap on the bottom of the car in a dead faint. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines leaped upon the running hoard of the machine and gazed in the direction Winters had pointed. Then, with a yell, he jumped to the ground, and, hurling people to the right and left, plunged through the mass of humanity like a maddened bull. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Officer Ryan, a strapping figure of a man, with the muscular figure of an athlete, who, a second before, had been in the prime of health, had suddenly thrown his arms in the air. For an instant he wove backwards and forwards, his face twisted, every muscle tensed, as if struggling against the unseen hands that were pulling him down. Then he gave voice to a shrill, hideous, agonized scream, and, lurching like a drunken man for a pace or two, crumpled up in a heap on the pavement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dozen of his brother officers leaped to his assistance. They were hurled back as if by an electric shock. Arising, they fought against the invisible force that held them in its power, but without avail. Open-mouthed, their feet fastened to the pavements as by steel bands, they were forced to stand and watch the torture of their comrade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Des Moines broke through the; edge of the crowd, the unknown power that held them in check lessened. In a body they dashed to the stricken man’s side and turned him on his back. His eyes were already glazing. His hands were cold and clammy. On his forehead was the sweat of death. He shivered spasmodically. Then his jaw dropped. Lessman had struck. “The Man Who Would Not Die” had won another victory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silence. Tense, nerve-racking silence. Eyes were peering, heads moving. On all sides excitement was visible on every face. But no one spoke a word. The agony was too great. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Boom!” High up in a. tower a clock was striking. Every eye was turned towards it. But still no word. Only the soul-straining, awful silence, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Boom!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Boom!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock was striking ten. Lessman had kept his word to the minute. A woman screamed. Her shrill, hysterical shriek broke the spell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then over the heads of the silent, awe-filled crowd rang a burst of laughter–cold, haunting, diabolical laughter–weird, mysterious–the gloating of a fiend. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandemonium broke loose. Those in the front lines, frozen with supernatural terror, turned, white-faced, from the horror that they had witnessed and sought an avenue of escape. None knew but the arch-fiend might continue–that, any moment, others might fall, blasted like a tree after a -lightning stroke. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men fought and struggled to flee from the invisible. Who knew ? Lessman might be he who stood beside you. Even now he might be seeking another victim! Nothing could stop him. He was omnipotent! Every man suspected his neighbor. The police labored with club and fist. It was like stemming the ocean’s tide with a shovel. It was a panic, a riot in which the stronger trampled the weaker under foot. There was no mercy–only a desire to escape from the spot. Men and women dropped, fainting, exhausted, dying where they fell, beneath the feet of their maddened fellows. Their dying screams only added to the fright of those who rushed over them. Automobiles, their drivers stricken by the fear that mastered all, dashed madly ahead, slaughtering and crippling. The pavement, covered with dead and wounded, was like a battlefield. It was a miniature hell–an inferno created by the diseased brain of a devil in human form. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the officers had finally completed their task and the street was cleared–when the last ambulance had departed with its ghastly load–Des Moines looked about him for Winters. He was gone. An officer remembered seeing the millionaire’s machine driving away, its owner huddled up in the back seat, shrieking and babbling, his shoulders shaking with hysterical sobs, his face wearing the look of a man who has just escaped from Hades. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector stood deep in thought, “He said that he’d speak to me! And yet–dammit all! The man never lived who could act such a part. It can’t be him!” And, with a shake of his head, he returned to his duties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VIII &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a lonely house in one of the outlying districts–a house set down in the midst of great trees and gardens, surrounded by a high stone wall–dwelt a man of extraordinary powers. To his neighbors he was merely an Oriental gentleman of wealth and refinement, who preferred solitude in an alien country to a position of magnificence and power in his own. But to the initiate–that little band of followers selected from every walk of life–he was the ambassador of a tiny group of learned men who, for centuries before Jesus, the Christ, walked upon this earth, have been striving to bring about the regeneration of the world. Their representatives are to be found in every large center of population, working quietly, unostentatiously, teaching, preaching, gaining an occasional recruit, ever content to bide their time, knowing that years are but seconds in the general scheme of the universe. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mahommed Gunga, the Master, as he was known to those who loved and obeyed him, was a truly wonderful man. Taken, when a child, by The Holy Ones, his life had been dedicated by them to the service of his fellow creatures. Masters of mystery, delving far beyond the comprehension of ordinary humans into the phenomena of life, they had poured their combined wisdom into his open ears. And, their task completed, they had sent him out into the world, as they had sent many others before him, to spread the propaganda of the great work to which they had pledged themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None knew the limits of his power, none the depths of his great learning. To him all things were possible. To him life’s mysteries were but commonplaces. Master of theosophy, philosophy, and the sciences, what, to the novitiate, seemed to savor of the weird, the mysterious, the occult, was to his mighty mind but the working of nature’s laws. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was to the shrine of The Master that Des Moines always journeyed when confronted by a puzzle past his comprehension. For the clear, reasoning power of the sage untangled riddles that, to the ordinary mind, appeared beyond solution. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it was to The Master that the inspector hurried as rapidly as his high-powered car would carry him after the Broadway horror had shown him the futility of his reasoning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IX &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He found The Master walking in the garden, a faraway look in his soft, dreamy eyes, in silent communion with nature. Upon the policeman’s arrival, however, his face lighted up and he shook hands warmly. For Mohammed Gunga had none of the methods of the charlatan; to his friends his life was an open book to be read by all who cared to take the time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Greetings, my friend,” he smiled. “What new problem brings you here this morning? For I dare not hope that so busy a man as yourself would deign to make a purely social call. Come walk beside me and tell me all about it.” He laughed sadly as he continued: “Will you never remember, my friend, that every atom has its master and recognizes his intelligence? Have we not been taught to know that we have but to seek the way by making the profound obeisance of the soul to the bright star that bums within?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines fell into step at his side and hastily sketched the events of the past thirty-six hours. For Mohammed Gunga did not keep in touch with the world; newspapers never passed his doorway. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the inspector completed his tale, The Master turned in his tracks and, placing his hands on the big man’s shoulders, said in a voice that quivered with emotion: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dear friend, you have rendered the cause a greater favor than you realize by bringing your problem to me. For Lessman, in his egotism, ha3 at last unmasked himself. Now we can fight him in the open. But I forget that you do not understand. Sit here on this bench with me and let me explain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Professor Darius Lessman is, without a doubt, the greatest intellect this or any other century has produced. He was employed at one time as teacher of psychology in a small, inland college. His great ability soon brought him to the attention of The Holy Men to whose cause we are all devoted. You know the lengths to which they will go to further the spreading of the great work. They sought him out. He became the favorite pupil of one in whose footsteps even I am not fitted to walk. He was tried in various ways and found not wanting. He was taught all–everything. His wonderful brain grasped in a few years that which others have spent a lifetime in learning. So proficient did he become that plans were made to send him across the waters for final instruction from those, the hem of whose garments you and I may never hope to touch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Creator of all things never intended that a man should have the brain that was bestowed upon Darius Lessman. The man is an anomaly. The devil must have had a hand in his making and, when his training was completed, took him for his own. For Lessman, crazed by the power he found was within him, conceived the idea of living forever. He believed that he was greater than the God who created him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For months he practiced in secret, attempting to transfer his soul from one human body to another at the command of his will. Failing, he sought his old Master, told him his secret and begged him for help. When the Master turned upon him in horror and loathing, he killed the good old man to protect his own devilish secret. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then he fled with a woman he had captivated by means of his diabolical wiles–a pure girl named Meta Vanetta, who, too, had been an humble pupil of the murdered Master. She became Lessman’s tool–his accomplice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Together, they worked out Lessman’s plans in some secret place, spreading death and destruction wherever they went in order to gain the human clay with which to work. We have followed them, tracking them from country to country, yet seldom daring to strike because of our knowledge that he was our superior. For Lessman is a monster–a man who laughs at death. And none has been found strong enough to kill his twisted soul. The cell was never made that could hold him. For he has but to discard his body and seize upon that of another. Many men of our faith have met him. He has killed them all by the power of his will. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The brain has not been made that can match his” in a duel of wills. Even I am fearful of him–and I am backed by the united intelligence of the Hob’ Men who are with me in spirit night and day. His is a mind gone wild– amuck, as you would say in the vernacular. For years 1 have prepared myself for [lie meeting. Am I fitted for the ordeal ? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I tell you, my friend, the time has come. Lessman must die! We must kill him for the sake of humanity! Not as one man kills another. We must kill his soul, even though we are forced to call upon the Holy Ones for aid. For the time you must forget that you are the policeman, and become the protector of mankind. We must gird ourselves for the battle, trusting in God to protect the right. Now do you understand?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines drew a trembling hand across his brow, from which the sweat was pouring. “God,” he muttered, hoarsely. “It’s horrible–unbelievable.” The Master patted his shoulder affectionately. “I realize it, my friend. Yet, to a certain extent, you have been trained to see that which, to the ordinary mind, appears obtuse. Multiply that which you know, and understand, by hundreds, and you comprehend my wisdom. And I am but an infant in intellect compared to Darius Lessman. “The man cares for but two things–riches and power. Seek for the man who would profit most by the death of Augustus Winters. And, when you have found him, return to me. Further than that I can tell you nothing. I must go now and, in prayer and meditation, prepare myself for the inevitable meeting.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Des Moines left the home , of The Master, his head in a whirl. Although his years of experience in grappling with criminality in all of its sickening forms had made him a man far beyond the ordinary in point of intellect, his brain was too well acquainted with the wonder-worker he had just left to doubt his veracity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had seen the terrible power of Lessman in the case of the unfortunate Ryan. The other officers who had battled against the unseen force were unable to add any information to what he already knew. They could only say that, for the instant, a will more powerful than their own had held them in check. What it was, they could not explain. Nor could they describe their sensations. Pondering over the matter as he whirled citywards the inspector could only shake his head. He was face to face with the greatest mystery he had ever tackled– a mystery so big that only The Master himself could fathom it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he came to a cross street, he suddenly changed his mind and directed the chauffeur to drive to the Winters home. He would again study the millionaire at close range. He was unable to reconcile himself to the belief that the slow-witted, hysterical man of money was the enormous intellect described by Mohammed Gunga. Yet, everything fitted in to make a case against Winters–only to tumble to pieces at the next turn. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was the telephone call. His men had investigated. Not only was the operator ready to swear that it had been Winters who called from booth number fourteen, but the cigar girl as well. The man had stopped at the cigar stand for an instant. He was well known to the girl in charge, who had addressed him by name, as had the clerk on duty at the time. Yet, three minutes later. Winters had answered the telephone at his own home ten miles away. Clearly, a man could not be in two places at the .same time. Nor was it within the power of any human being, by any modern means of transportation, to transport himself that distance within the time given. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilkins answered the inspector’s ring. His master was in the parlor sitting beside the body of his beloved wife. He would announce the inspector. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second later he returned and ushered Des Moines into the big reception hall. The inspector shook hands with the millionaire. Then, his eyes on the other’s face, he plunged immediately into the reason for his call. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Winters,” he said. “I believe that I am on the right track at last. But I need some information that only you can give me. Will you do it ?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no hesitancy on the part of the man of wealth. “Ask me anything you wish, inspector. I will answer your question to the best of my ability.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines bored on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Winters,” he said, sharply, “who is your heir?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The millionaire started. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why, er–I don’t understand what you are getting at?” he exclaimed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just this. If I am correct in my guess, your life is in danger. In view of this morning’s happenings, I am at last firmly convinced that Mrs. Winters’ death was nothing more or less than a coldblooded murder! So, too, was the death of the maid! I will admit that several times I have had my doubts. Now I know!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winters started back, aghast. “Horrible ! Horrible!” he cried. “It is hard to believe–yet it must be true. But who could have so hated my poor wife as to take her life?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inspector continued relentlessly. “With Mrs. Winters out of the way, it is my belief that you will be the next to go. We must protect you. Now who is going to profit by all this deviltry? Have you made a will ?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winters put his hand to his head. “Surely, it cannot be true. You cannot believe that they–mere children–” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who arc they, man?. Speak up!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My nephew, Thomas De Pew, and my niece, Cora Dayton, his cousin. Everything I have will go to them. Mrs. Winters had no near relatives. My will has been made for months. Of course, had my wife lived, she would have inherited all.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do they live in the city?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They make their home with me. They have lived here since childhood. Both are orphans.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I would like to talk with them, question them, without their knowing the reason. Will you kindly summon them ? Tell them that I am merely seeking additional data for my report.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winters, white-faced, arose. “I will do as you wish, inspector,” he said, slowly. “But you are wrong in suspecting those children. Thomas is but nineteen years of age. His cousin is nearly a year younger. Theirs cannot be the brains that planned this horrible outrage.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stepped into the adjoining room, only to reappear, an instant later, with the information that both of the young people had driven downtown for the afternoon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspector Des Moines left the Winters home feeling that he had made no material progress. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XI &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funeral services for the late Mrs. Winters had been held and the body tenderly laid away in the family vault in Rose Hill cemetery. At the same hour, in another part of the city, amid more humble surroundings, was held the funeral of Dolly Matthews, the maid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alone in his office, Inspector Des Moines sat scanning the afternoon papers. They were still filled with criticisms of the police administration. Nor did the inspector blame them greatly. For he was obliged to confess himself beaten–defeated at every turn of the road. He had attended the funeral of Mrs. Winters in person. Several of his best plain-clothes men had mingled with the crowd. Others had been present at the funeral of the maid. Their reports were one and the same. There was nothing–absolutely nothing–to report. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the telephone, he had given The Master the results of his interview with Winters. Mohammed Gunga had advised him to say nothing, do nothing, until Lessman again showed his hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost in reverie, he went over every phase of the case. A stone wall confronted him. There was nothing upon which he could even base a theory. Even though he succeeded in pinning the crimes on Winters, what jury would believe the incredible story ? There was not even a motive. He would be laughed out of court. Mohammed Gunga was his only hope. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The telephone tinkled jarringly, startling him out of his daydreams. The voice»which answered his gruff “Hello!” was that of a stranger, agitated, jerky. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Inspector, this is Thomas De Pew, Augustus Winters’ nephew. For the love of God, come out here quick! Something awful has happened. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know what it is. I can’t explain. I only know that a stranger called here shortly after we returned from the funeral and inquired for my uncle. Wilkins, the butler, heard him request a private interview. Uncle Gus took him into his study and closed the door. We supposed that he had departed, for, later, my uncle left the house for a short stroll–or, at least, we so imagined. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A few minutes ago Wilkins entered the study. He found the body of the stranger lying on the floor–stone dead! No, there is not a mark of violence on him. The physician–Doctor Bennett– has just completed his examination. “And my uncle has not yet returned.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XII &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the telephone, Des Moines reported the latest angle of the case to Mohammed Gunga. Then he drove to the latter’s residence and picked him up on his way to the Winters home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The white-faced butler admitted them, trembling like a leaf as he ushered them into the presence of young De Pew, a slender youth trying hard to appear manly in spite of his agitation. A moment later they were joined by Miss Dayton, the niece, a beautiful girl whose eyes were swollen and red from weeping, although she seemed to hold herself under better control than did the boy. The inspector briefly introduced The Master as one of his men versed in subtle poisons, brought along for the purpose of detecting if any such had been used in making away with the stranger found in the study. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hasty examination of the dead man proved the correctness of young De Pew’s report. He was a rough appearing individual, evidently a laborer, far from the sort of person a man of Winters’ refinement and wealth would be likely to be on intimate terms with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohammed Gunga arose from the stooping position over the dead man and turned to De Pew. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Darius Lessman,” he said, in the conversational tone of one polished gentleman addressing another, “the time for unmasking is at hand! We meet at last! It is your soul or mine! Prepare yourself for the ordeal! Summon, if you are able, the powers of darkness. I warn you that behind me lies all of the great strength of the Holy Ones–and only you know what that means. Are you ready for the trial?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an instant there was silence. Then, with a wild shriek, the girl ran screaming from the room. Des Moines stepped back a pace, startled by the sudden accusation. Yet he knew the Master too well to doubt the correctness of his charges. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;De Pew’s eyes glared angrily. He seemed about to leap at the throat of his accuser. Then, with a shrug of his thin shoulders, he chuckled–a throaty, diabolical, gleeful burst of mirth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As you wish, my dear Mohammed Gunga! As you wish. I will warn you, as you have warned me. I intend to kill you, damn you! Yes, and the infernal meddler with you, too. I’ll kill you as I killed the others.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He rubbed his hands together gleefully, giving way again to his unholy mirth. “Yes, and, by God, I’ll use your carcasses as I used this piece of carrion on the floor, there. Think you that you can stop me–that you, in your littleness, can end a career such as mine ? I am Lessman, The Man Who Can Not Diet I’ll he chief of police for a day I Ha! Ha! Yes, and I’ll wear the robes of The Master. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, fools. Meta, the woman I love, is she who has just left the room. Together, we killed Mrs. Winters– blasted her as we will blast you, Yes, I’ll blast you, curse you! I can throw my will across the continent. Think you, then, that you can defeat me? I got Des Moines here to end him, knowing that he would bring you along. With you gone, the world is mine! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the body of Mrs. Winters, Meta left this house. She came here in the body of Dolly, Ha! Ha! It was a puzzle for the fools of policemen, trying to figure out how the body of the maid got into the coffin of the mistress. I love puzzles. I worked it all out to attract your attention–as I knew it eventually would–my dear Mohammed Gunga. You were getting too close to my tracks–you and your hellish gang! With you gone, none will be left on this side of the water who can hope to match their strength with mine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My only regret is that I didn’t blast that damned salesman, Johnson, who blocked our game when we stole the brooch. I was the chauffeur, as you have already guessed. I grew tenderhearted–fool that I am. When he seized Meta, he forced her to quit the body she was occupying and enter that of the dead woman we had, in the machine, ready for just such an emergency. I’ll get him yet, though, damn him! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I killed Winters, inspector, the same night that I telephoned to you. Ha, it was funny. I left his body hidden in a room I keep downtown for just such purposes. Then I threw my soul across the space and into the body I now occupy in time to answer your telephone call. I knew that you would trace the call and seek to trap me. I wanted to puzzle you. It has been a real pleasure for me to play with you. For I give you credit for having more intelligence than the average detective. I knew that sooner or later, though, you would get beyond your depth and call for aid from Mohammed Gunga. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where is Winters’ body hidden now? That’s my business, fools! It’s hidden away where I can use it again if the occasion ever demands–after Meta and I get through using the Winters millions, possibly. Your policeman? O, yes, I killed him–blasted him from the automobile while I was talking to you. I kept my promise, did I not? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And now, both of you, prepare to die! I, Lessman, the Man Who Will Not Die, will it!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XIII &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Des Moines felt an icy sensation creep over him. Then came a peculiar numbness. He struggled against it. Clammy fingers seemed to clutch his throat! He was choking! He staggered like a drunken man, seeking an avenue of escape. A veil of darkness seemed to weigh upon his eyes. Tighter and tighter grew the bands about him. And, then, screaming like an hysterical woman, he fell to the floor, unconscious. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long he lay there he never knew. Probably only a few seconds. He awakened suddenly. For an instant he imagined himself dead. He opened his eyes. Over him stood the Master, calm, self-reliant, facing the monster. Silently the two men, only a few yards apart, waged the greatest battle the world will ever know–the battle of wills–a duel between the Powers of Darkness and the forces of Good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly– slowly– slowly, Lessman seemed to weaken. Great drops of sweat stood out on his forehead. His breath came in asthmatic pants. He struggled to save himself, to concentrate his powerful will for a final effort, but in vain. Opposed to him was a will greater than his own–the united will of the thousands who had devoted their lives to the work of uplifting mankind–the will of the holy men of India. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His legs trembled. His fingers twitched jerkily. Then, as he sank to the floor, he made a final effort to escape. From his body emanated a thin vapor–an aura. It was his soul attempting flight. It spread across the room like a nauseous miasma, smoke-like, cloudy, repellent–hellish! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to The Master’s will, it drew itself together. Slowly–oh, so slowly–as if fighting to the very last, it drew nearer and nearer to the man to whose mind it acknowledged the mastery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last, it was but a tiny, smoky, grey ball of vapor. The Master held forth his hand and it hovered over his palm. He pressed his fingers together. When he opened them a tiny particle of grayish power lay within his hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the house rang the bloodcurdling shriek of a woman–a single, despairing wail of anguish! Then, through the door floated another wraith. For a second it hesitated. Then it mingled with the ashes of its lover in the Master’s hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohammed Gunga blew upon his palm. The powder vanished into nothingness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He. extended his hand to Des Moines and assisted him to his feet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That is the end! Only you and I know the truth. Let us depart. The Monster is dead!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE END &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-man-who-would-not-die/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-man-who-would-not-die/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Man Who Was Seven</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-i&quot;&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A man cannot be in two places at the same time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That is a law of physics-—isn’t it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But how about the other lazy, of evidence, and your own senses? If you saw and heard a man in that impossible situation or condition, which would you believe, the law or your own eyes and ears?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But the thing is impossible!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So? Then how about this:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ON ONE of those fine Italian spring mornings that pass for summer in the Puget Sound country, there entered the Savoy Hotel, Seattle, a man who ordinarily would not call for specific description, but who, for the sake of this argument, we need to identify particularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stood out from the world about five feet eleven inches, weighed approximately one hundred and sixty to one hundred and seventy pounds, was apparently in his late thirties or early forties, wore a neatly trimmed brown mustache and beard of the cut known as Vandyke, spectacles with large, rim¬less, egg-shaped lenses, a soft black broad-brimmed hat, blue serge suit with double-breasted coat, black tie, low tan shoes, carried a light-weight gray overcoat, a black Gladstone bag and a sole-leather suitcase. He walked with a slight but noticeable limp of the left leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relinquishing coat and bags to a bellboy, the newcomer nodded pleasantly to the clerk and registered, in a dis¬tinctly legible hand, the name “Samuel Smith,” without address. This done, he set his watch by that of the clerk— it was just 10:02 a. m.—received his key and followed the bell-boy to room 314. Tipping the boy generously but not lavishly, he asked that the hotel valet and public stenographer be sent to him. To the one he gave a suit of clothes for pressing; to the other he dictated two short letters. Returning to the lobby, he bought a dollar’s worth of cigars, asked to be directed to the Totem National Bank, glanced at his watch and, commenting audibly upon the time, 10:48, walked out into the crowd on Second Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing remarkable or unusual about that, nothing that does not occur, in a general way, in a thousand hotels all over the land every day in the year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True. But wait a moment. The case is not stated yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that same fine Italian spring morning of the same day, is this same city of Seattle, Washington, there en¬tered the Butler Hotel, a man who ordinarily would not call for specific description, but who, for the sake of this argument, we need to identify par¬ticularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stood out from the world about five feet eleven inches, weighed ap¬proximately one hundred and sixty to one hundred and seventy pounds, was apparently in his late thirties or early forties, wore a neatly trimmed brown mustache and beard of the cut known as Vandyke, spectacles with large egg-shaped lenses, black tie, low tan shoes, blue serge suit with double-breasted coat, a soft black broad-brimmed hat, carried a light weight gray overcoat, a black Gladstone bag and sole-leather suitcase. He walked with a slight but noticeable limp of the left leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relinquishing coat and bags to a bell¬boy, the newcomer nodded pleasantly to the clerk and registered, in a dis¬tinctly legible hand, the name “Samuel Smith,” without address. This done, he set his watch by that of the clerk— it was just 10:02 a.m.—received his key and followed the bell-boy to room 264. Tipping the boy generously but not lavishly, he asked that the hotel valet and public stenographer be sent to him. To the one he gave a suit of clothes for pressing; to the other dic¬tated two short letters. Returning to the lobby, he bought a dollar’s worth of cigars, asked to be directed to the To¬tem National Bank, glanced at his watch and commented audibly upon the time, 10:48, and walked out into the crowded street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That makes it just a little more un¬usual—eh, what? But don’t be impa¬tient or jump at conclusions. There is more to come.
On one of those fine Italian spring mornings that pass for summer in the Puget Sound country there entered the Rainier Grand Hotel, Seattle, a man who ordinarily—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there’s no use going through it all again in the style of “One dark and stormy night in the Carpathian moun¬tains a robber band gathered about their chief—.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clinch the matter, a man of ex¬actly the same appearance as described above entered, at the same hour and minute, signed the same name in the same handwriting, did exactly the same things, made the same remarks, and left at the same minute, not only the Savoy and Bullet, but also the Rainier Grand, Washington, Lincoln, Seattle and Frye Hotels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hotel clerks are observing people, as men go, and each of them, of all seven hotels, not only stated the facts as here set down but swore to them, with many additional and confirmatory details you have not been bothered with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk about your alibis! Most men are content with proving that they were at some one other place at a given time, but here was a man—if the singular pronoun be correct—who was in seven different places at the same time, with some thirty-odd reputable witnesses able to testify to the fact, if it was a fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sort of thing isn’t an alibi—it is the fourth dimension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-ii&quot;&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never would have taken Jim Carranaugh for a detective. He was too obvious. Entirely too big. Too big by a number of inches, both ways. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, he could and had, by strenuous starvation, trained down to two hundred and eighty pounds; also, he had reached four hundred and one. Some place between these two ex¬tremes might be called normal, if Jim could be called a normal human at any time. Four inches and a half above six feet and almost an equal distance around his equator makes a fairly siz¬able man, so it is no wonder he at¬tracted and held attention wherever he went. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for all his size, Carranaugh was nimble of hand and foot as well as of wit, and could catch a car or a culprit as readily as the point of a joke. His command of polyglot American was the marvel and joy of his friends. The English language could not be broken into too small or too irregular pieces to escape his power of mimicry. Had he not been the able detective he was, he would have made a rare- character actor; had he not been so good an actor he might not have been so efficient an officer of the law. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-iii&quot;&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Totem National Bank of Se¬attle occupies a one-story building of its own just off Pioneer Square in the older part of the city, close to the wholesale and commission firms, ware¬houses and shipping interests that form the bulk of its depositors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westward to the present shore or wharfline is all made ground. The lower layers of this are, or were, saw¬dust and slabs from the sawmills that were one of the earliest industries of the little town that was to become a great city. To this substratum was added the refuse of the growing com¬munity, until finally the casual and in¬determinate merged into the planned and ordered earth-and-stone fill upon which paved streets and huge buildings rest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outer and western edge of this district still is, however, in more or less of its earlier formative state, piled and planked over for much of the area be¬tween Western Avenue and Elliott Bay. Beneath these streets and their wooden structures the rising and fall¬ing tides slosh about and the industri¬ous toredo lunches on fir and spruce with creosote dressing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a certain summer Monday morn¬ing the steamship Bertha arrived at her dock in Seattle, bringing from Alaska via Skagway a shipment of $200,000 in gold—bars, nuggets and dust—con¬signed to the Totem National Bank. As was sometimes the custom in those days, this gold was displayed heaped up in the bank’s windows to satisfy the curiosity, whet the avaricious appetite and inspire the confidence of passersby. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comfortable fortune was ex¬hibited during banking hours on Tues¬day and Wednesday under the jealous eyes of two guards stationed within the bank and two others at either side of the window on the street outside. There really was no danger of robbery. The heap of gold weighed over a thousand pounds and the window was heavily and closely barred inside and out. The guards were nearly as much a part of the peep-show as the gold, the addi¬tional and necessary touch to give it the proper importance in the public eye. At night the gold was transferred from the window to the bank vault, with due ceremony, lapsing there to its proper measure of importance in a bank that reckoned its resources by the million. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for the stage setting. Now for the first scene of the comedy-drama. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-iv&quot;&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it had better be called pro¬logue, since it happened nearly a week before the arrival and display of the gold—to be exact, on the very day that the Bertha cleared from Skagway. At that time it attracted no greater atten¬tion than any other of the many rou¬tine transactions of the Totem Na¬tional, being merely the leasing of a safe-deposit box, one of the largest, such as generally is used for the safe keeping of large books or other bulky records of value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lessor gave his name as Seth C. Seeley; address, temporary. Hotel Savoy, Seattle; permanent. Bankers’ Trust Company, New York; business, dealer in securities. In less than an hour after receiving his card of identi¬fication and key Seeley returned with a large parcel heavily wrapped and corded, apparently of considerable weight and of a size that just fitted into and filled the box. Remarking pet¬tishly that the Totem National should lie prepared to supply its customers with more adequate accommodations, Seeley grumblingly hired the two ad¬joining boxes of the same size as the first and in turn filled them with sim¬ilar parcels. These, like the first, he carried and put in place with his own hands, despite their evident weight, roughly declining all assistance prof¬fered by the banks employees. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday morning of that week Daniels, first assistant cashier of the Totem National, unlocked the vault to withdraw the cash necessary for the day’s business and to superintend the removal of the $200,000 gold to its place in the limelight. He took one step within the battleship-armored doorway, gasped, and took two steps backward, yelling for help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two entirely sufficient causes for the first assistant cashier’s excitement. The most apparent was the body of a man lying sprawled on the vault floor, very evidently and most completely dead. The second, to Dan¬iels’ trained eyes, the almost equally obvious fact that the vault had been looted—of the $200,000 in gold and he did not know how much more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reasons that all bankers will un¬derstand and sympathize with, but toward which newspaper men hold very different attitudes, the officials of the Totem National made every effort and used every means at their command to keep all news of the robbery from the public, to such good effect that no sus¬picion of any of the happenings here related reached the newspapers until the whole incident was history. The body of the dead man added annoying complications to this hushing-up proc¬ess, but the power of money is great even when it lies fallow in banks, so no insinuation of bribe tendering or ac¬ceptance is intended here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far be it from me to even remotely suggest that a banker would give or a policeman take money for the suppres¬sion of the truth. The police were only too willing to keep the whole thing quiet until they should have arrested the thief and murderer, which consum¬mation, they assured the bank, would be a matter of only hours or days, as is the optimistic, not to say egotistic way of policemen the world over. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the views on publicity held by the board of directors of the Totem National, ‘they were not disposed to take their loss philosophically or inac¬tively. While they assured Chief Stein, of the Seattle police, that they had every confidence in his zeal and ability to both capture the thief or thieves and recover the stolen valuables, they also availed themselves of the additional services of the Pinkertons and the Gov¬ernment secret service men, the latter being interested by reason of the fact that part of the loot taken was some thousands of dollars’ worth of revenue and excise stamps temporarily in the care of the bank while in transit to other points of distribution. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this indicates, the $200,000 worth of gold was not all of the treasure that was missing, the total figure reaching to over the million mark when the care¬ful check of the vault’s contents had been made. This sum was made up, in addition to the gold brought by the Bertha, of gold coin, bank notes and easily negotiable securities. Silver spe¬cie, bills of small denomination, and papers of problematical value to the thieves were found scattered about the floor of the vault around and under the dead body, discarded as contemptu¬ously as this now insensate and useless clay. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body was that of a man about five feet eleven inches in height, weight one hundred and sixty to one hundred and seventy pounds, in his late thirties or early forties, with neatly trimmed brown mustache and Vandyke beard. It was dressed in a suit of blue serge, double-breasted coat, tan shoes. On the floor near by lay a lightweight gray overcoat, a broad brimmed black soft hat, the broken pieces of what had been spectacles with large, rimless, egg-shaped lenses, a black Gladstone bag and a sole-leather suitcase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last named was empty, but the bag was partially filled with pajamas, shirts, collars and the usual toilet acces¬sories of a man particular about his ap¬pearance. In the pockets of the clothes there was found nothing by which to identify the dead man except a card-case stamped with and containing cards engraved with the name, “Samuel Smith,” and receipted bills made out in the same name and all bearing the same date, that of the previous day, from seven Seattle hotels. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the foregoing might apply in a general way to the body of any dead man under normal circumstances. What took this body out of the ordinary was not only its inexplicable presence in the locked and guarded vault but also the fact that from the back there protrud¬ed the handle of a large hunting knife —one of the elkhorn variety never car¬ried except by chechahco hunters. The long blade was buried in the body just below and to the right of the left shoulder blade, between it and the spine, and had been driven in with such a forceful blow that the haft made an indentation in the flesh about the wound. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inquiry, conducted quietly and circumspectly out of regard for the tender feelings of the Totem National, developed the fact that a man answer¬ing to this description and the name of Samuel Smith had stopped at each and all of the hotels indicated by the bills, that he had settled his accounts and de¬parted the day before, Wednesday, for a destination unknown to any of the clerks, leaving no forwarding address. But the policeman in plain clothes who reported on this feature of the case was not gifted with imagination above “carrying a message to Garcia,” and so he did only what he was told to do and asked only what he had been told to ask, thus he overlooked the coincidence in the times of arrival and departure of the said Smith, which later was de¬veloped. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chief of Police and the city de¬tectives working under him on the case were unanimous in their opinion of the dead man’s part in the problem. There was not the slightest doubt. Chief Stein declared, and the others echoed, that the man must have been one of the gang that turned the trick, and that he had been murdered by his confederates dur¬ing a quarrel over the division of the spoils. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suitcase, they pointed out, un¬questionably had been provided for carrying away this Smith’s share of the proceeds of the robbery, and its empti¬ness was conclusive evidence that he, in turn, had been cheated of that share and stabbed when he attempted to pro¬test. To them, the police, the dead man simply was one crook the less to require their attention—and good rid¬dance. Nor, to them, did he even pro¬vide one of their dearly beloved clues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government officers were not in¬terested at all in the death or murder, except for its possible value as an indi¬cation of the gang’s identity, presup¬posing that there was a gang that had turned the trick. The man’s face and description were not on file at any po¬lice headquarters in the country and cabled inquiry abroad did not serve to identify him as a known or suspected criminal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pinkerton operatives, acting di¬rectly for the bank and the Bankers’ Protective Association, were, like the secret service men, far more interested in the recovery of the vanished treasure than in avenging the death of an un¬known and, presumably, unimportant stranger, who probably had received only his just deserts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the main facts of the case were, and so they remained without a single illuminating ray of enlightenment at the end of a week after the discovery of the crime. Of course the police ar-rested a number of tramps, I. W. W.’s, ex-convicts and others known unfavor¬ably to the force, but were forced re¬luctantly to let them go again, for lack of a single item of even police evidence that would warrant their further deten¬tion as suspicious characters. That is one of the annoyances of police ad¬ministration under our puerile system of limiting the power of the guardians of our wealth and safety. Now in Russia— &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, yes, Stein reported daily to the officials of the Totem National that he was “making progress.” But nothing whatever had been discovered to indi¬cate the means taken by the thieves to enter or leave the vault or the bank building itself. The guards, regular and special watchmen, the patrolman on the beat, had seen nothing, heard nothing. All doors and locks were in perfect condition, as they had been left the night before the robbery. There were no signs of violence other than the dead body and the litter within the vault. No tool-marks, no fingerprints, no tampering with combinations, noth¬ing that appeared in any way different from the way it should be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treasure had disappeared. The dead man’s body had appeared. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was all and it remained all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until— &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-v&quot;&gt;CHAPTER V&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I came in for a little help, Tom,” said Jim Carranaugh to Tom Peiperson, head of the Seattle Advertising Service, as the big man entered his friend’s office. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry, but I’m down to small change. If that will do you any—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not bracing you I am—this time. I want a little advice, maybe a little help into the bargain.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cheapest thing I know.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m up against a queer sort of proposition.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s have it.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You noticed about that last ship¬ment of gold from Skagway—two hun¬dred thousand dollars’ worth on the Bertha?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. Saw it in the window of the Totem National. Now if they only would let me handle their advertising I’d—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Never mind about that now, Tom. If you can help me pull off this stunt I’ll whack up more than all the banks in Seattle would spend for advertising in a year.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That sounds reasonable. Proceed.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can you—will you keep mum if I tell you something that the newspapers would break their city editors’ necks to get hold of?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can and will.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen: That two hundred thousand in gold, along with over eight hundred thousand more in money and securities, was stolen from the Totem National a week ago last night.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What! Who? Stolen! When? I haven’t seen a word about it in the papers. Where’d you get the story? Have they caught—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;” ‘Cease firing.’ The ‘what’ I’ve just told you. I’ll give you details in a minute. The ‘who’ is for us to find out. You haven’t seen anything about it in the papers for the very good reason that they neither know nor suspect any¬thing about it—and are not apt to un¬less and until the thing is cleared up.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then how, where did you—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve just come from an interview with old man Snedeker—president of the Totem, you know. He sent for me this morning, swore me to secrecy by every oath a banker knows and told me all about it. Seems Stein, the Pinkertons, and the secret service men have been working at the case for a week without finding the smell of a smell. Snedeker said he was disgusted with the whole outfit, had heard of the work I did in that ‘Praxiteles’ affair— I didn’t interrupt to tell him that you did as much or more than I in clearing that up—and that if I could do as well in this case for him there’d be a cool fifty thousand in it for me—-and no questions asked. I gathered that he meant he was much more anxious about the bank’s recovering the money than about catching the thieves, though of course he wants them snagged too if possible. So it’s up to us. Think of it, Tom! Fifty thousand bucks!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sounds very luscious. But why the ‘us’? Where do I come in?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fifty-fifty with me. Or, better— twenty-five—twenty-five.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But you’re the only original Sher¬lock, Jim. I’m ready to tackle any problem in the advertising line, but when it comes to—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How about the ‘Praxiteles’ case?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That wasn’t de-teck-eting. That was just advertising. You don’t ex¬pect me to run a personal, do you, say¬ing: ‘The gentlemen who robbed the Totem National Bank will learn of something to their disadvantage if they will call at the office of James Carranaugh, Sleuth.’?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No-o-o. Not quite that.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“‘Not quite’! What in the name of the Chilkat gods do you expect me to do?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing—that is, I want you to tell me. I thought you might be able to help me locate or find out something about a chap by the name of ‘Samuel Smith,’ who stopped at seven Seattle hotels one day last week.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s that? At seven hotels? Is this Smith a man or a convention?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s one of the things that I don’t know, that we have to find out. But he, or they, is, are—that is, were—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Give her more gas, Jim, your en¬gine’s missing fire.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t josh, Tom. This is the biggest thing I’ve ever had a chance to tackle, one of the biggest ever pulled off on the Coast, and if I—we can make good be¬fore the government men, Pinkertons and police, our reputation’s made, and with that reward we can buy that island in the South Seas and all—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wait until you catch your hare. To return to this Samuel Smith—where does he come in?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He stopped at seven hotels—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you said. That’s unusual but not necessarily criminal.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And they found him in the vault.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hold on! What’s that? ‘Found him in the vault’? I thought you said, a minute ago, that they hadn’t caught anyone, didn’t know who did it? If they’ve got him what’s the use of—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’ve got Smith all right—at the morgue. But that hasn’t helped any— yet.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At the—he’s dead?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As dead as they make ‘em. About eight inches of knife in his back.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Better back ‘way up, Jim, and tell me the whole story if you want me to help, if I can help you at all. It’s begin¬ning to get interesting.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’ll get a heap more so before we’re through, or I miss my guess. Well, Snedeker told me—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no need of repeating what Carranaugh told Peiperson of what Snedeker had told him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the detective had finished re¬counting the details of the robbery the advertising man smoked thoughtfully for nearly five minutes, gazing out of his window at the Olympics with their perennial snow peaks like old men in nightcaps. Coming out of his trance with a jerk Peiperson grabbed his hat and was halfway out of the door of his private office before Carranaugh could heave himself to his fret &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where’re you going?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To those hotels. Come on! Hurry! You have the list? Must get busy. There’s something queer there. Might as well start at that as well as at any other place, now that you’ve roped me into this. And I’d have murdered you if you had left me out! Then we can go down to the morgue and the bank and—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest was lost to Carranaugh as Peiperson stopped to tell Chris, his of¬fice boy, that he probably would not be back that afternoon and to tell any possible callers that he was busy figur¬ing on a big contract. “And that’s no lie!” he said to Jim as they ran for the descending elevator. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going from one hotel to another un¬til they had talked with the clerks and attaches of all seven they gradually pieced together the amazing and per¬plexing problem of the apparent seven¬fold identity of Samuel Smith. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they left the Hotel Butler, the last on Carranaugh’s list, Jim uttered a piously emphatic belief in his future eternal condemnation, and Tom Peiper¬son agreed, for both of them. Mulling, wordless, over this mystery within a mystery, they walked over to the morgue and as silently checked up the items of the dead man’s former appear¬ance that coincided exactly with the seven times told description they had just listened to. Discuss it from every angle, they were no nearer a solution when, within a block of the Totem National, Peiperson halted, saying: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No use both of us covering the same ground—there’s plenty for each of us to do, and then some. You go on to the bank and have Snedeker let you examine that vault, as you suggested, and pick up anything more you can about the way the body of Smith looked when they found it. I don’t suppose any of ‘em had the brains to take a flashlight of the vault interior before they disturbed the layout. That’s what comes of keeping the newspaper boys out of it! If they had been let in on it from the jump-off we wouldn’t have to be depending upon the alleged mem-ories of a lot of incompetent witnesses who have probably forgotten most of what they did see and imagine a lot that never was, they’d have a detailed and exact description by someone who knew how to see and what to look for. This hush stunt makes me tired.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But in that case maybe we wouldn’t have had a chance at the fifty thou¬sand.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s so. Maybe not. Anyway, it’s too late now. While you are at the bank I’ll get busy and see if I can learn any more about this ‘Samuel Smith’. Talk about your alibis 1 Meet me at my office—wait for me or I will for you. Adios.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-vi&quot;&gt;CHAPTER VI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was close to nine o’clock that eve¬ning when a tired, hungry, perplexed and perspiring advertising man let him¬self into his office to find an equally hungry and perplexed detective await¬ing him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, what’d you find?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How about it?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your lead, Tom.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It won’t take me long to tell. Smith left town the day before the bank was burgled.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Left town! But the dead—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, alive. Six times or six of him. He took boat for Victoria, San Fran¬cisco and Skagway, and train for Spo¬kane, Portland, and Vancouver, B. C.”  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The same day?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The same day.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The same Smith?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The same Samuel Smith—or a man who is described as looking exactly like him and who used that name.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I tell you he’s dead.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe so, maybe so. But he wasn’t last Wednesday, not six of him.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But he couldn’t—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, he couldn’t, any more than he could have done the same things at the same times at seven different hotels. ^But they could.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I get you! There were seven of him—then.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Seven is right—seven men who looked alike, who dressed and acted in the same way according to a carefully prepared and rehearsed schedule, each of whom appeared, did his little stunt, and disappeared by and on the appoint¬ed minutes.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But that lets them out of cracking the vault—if they left the day before. Everything was all right up to mid¬night Wednesday a week ago.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Six of them left town that Tues¬day.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Six? Six! Then the seventh turned the trick and—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aren’t you forgetting the dead man found in the vault with a knife in his ribs?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I’ll be—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You probably will, if you continue to insist on it. But don’t let’s worry about that—yet. I’m anxious to hear what you found at the bank. There’s nothing except the results that is inter-esting about my afternoon’s work. I simply made the rounds of the railroads and steamship offices, depots and docks, until I satisfied myself beyond any doubt that all six and only six Samuel Smiths had left for the places I named, that they actually had gone and not merely pretended to. I would have thought the seventh one had taken an automobile for his getaway if it had not been for the man in the vault. He com¬pletes the count.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That surely lets them out of it—at least of getting away with the million. But if they didn’t—then why all the acting? They must have been mixed up in it in some way, or one of them wouldn’t be in the morgue. And I was almost ready to finger Snedcker’s check! Damn!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then you found something at the bank?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I did—or I think I did. I can’t be ¬sure until—but wait until I tell you. I told Snedeker what I wanted and he gave me the run of the whole place— but with that idiot Daniels tagging at my heels and blatting every second about the ‘effrontery of the miscreants’ in picking on the Totem National for their ‘dastardly outrage.’ To hear him you’d think that the Totem was the only bank that ever had been cracked, that it was nothing short of sacrilege and high treason for rude hands to touch even a deposit slip belonging to it. If Daniels was judge and jury the thieves would be convicted on sight and boiled in oil—when they’re caught. And he thinks the whole city, state and coun¬try administration should come to a hall until the heavy hand of the law is laid upon them—and that of the Totem Na¬tional on its million. He got on my nerves until I wanted to hit him, choke him, anything to stop his incessant cackle—until I discovered what I think I discovered. Then I didn’t hear his clack any more, though he kept it up without interruption. He—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, cut the Daniels part now, Jim Tell me what you found.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I think I found the way the thieves or thief got into the vault.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You did?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Think, mind you. I’m not sure and can’t be until I get a chance to investi¬gate further. If I’m right I don’t want Snedeker to know about it—yet. Not until we are ready to spring the whole story. He might go blabbing to the cops and spill our fat in the fire. They would try to grab all the credit and nose in oh the reward. Then where would our island be? We don’t want—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For the love of Mike, Jim, can the soliloquy and get down to cases. What did you find?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m telling you fast as I can, ain’t I? Of course, if you want to call in every flattie on the force to share our pie or take it all away from us and put that island in the ‘too rnuchee bime-by’—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peiperson threw up his hands in mock despair and Jim, grinning, got down to eases as exhorted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I had gone over every inch of the vault—walls, floor, ceiling, every nook and corner—several times without see¬ing a single thing out of kilter, and was standing thinking what to do next, wishing Daniels would shut up long enough to let me think uninterruptedly for a second, when I noticed one of the plates in the floor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The vault is built up, Snedeker told me, of three-inch chrome steel plates, three feet square, bolted together un¬derneath like those of a battleship and set in concrete. The vault, the whole building, in fact, rests on solid ground, Snedeker said, without cellar or space of any kind below the level of the street. Seems they were afraid of wa¬ter in that locality. He had assured me that our burglars could not have broken in from underground whatever other route they may have taken. Of course, I took his say-so on this point for what it might be worth, and no more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But as I looked at that plate in the middle of the vault floor I began to suspect that his confidence was not based on any firmer foundation than his building. The plate looked just like any of the others. It was the appear¬ance of the lines where it joined the four around it that made me kneel down for closer examination. And. you know, I don’t stoop my proud stomach any more than 1 have to. Luckily Daniels was puttering around absorbed in his monologue of Gottstraling all hank burglars and paying no particular attention to what I was doing. His opinion of detectives, I had gathered, was only one point bet¬ter than it was of burglars. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What first had attracted my atten¬tion was no more than that the lines of demarcation between this particular plate and the others seemed a bit wider than the corresponding lines elsewhere and quite a bit dirtier, as if they were filled with greasy dust. When I knelt I found I was right about both—they zee re wider and they were dirtier. It was greasy dust or dusty grease and deeper than I could probe with my fingernail, though the similar lines near¬by were not depressed over a few hun¬dredths of an inch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I confess that my hand trembled as I opened the blade of my knife and thrust it into those cracks—not in one place only but in a dozen, on all four sides of the plate. And each time it went clear in its full length without meeting an)’ obstruction! I scraped out a little bit of that ‘grease’—I’ll show it to you in a minute—and then smoothed over all the holes that I had made. What do you think of that. Sticking an ordinary knife blade through chrome steel!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s look at that sample of ‘grease’.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carranaugh took his wallet from his pocket and from it a cigarette-paper-wrapped pellet of a greasy gray steel color. It was odorless, had the feeling and consistency of paraffin filled with small grit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And then?” asked Peiperson, laying the gray pellet carefully on the desk beside him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then, more with the idea of getting Daniels away from that vault where he might happen to see what I had seen than with any idea of finding anything more, I asked to he shown the other vaults. I went through them all hut discovered nothing until we came to the one used for the safe-deposit de¬partment, next to and directly east of the one from which the money had been taken. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the floor of this vault, and, as far as I could judge without making measurements, in direct line with the other loose plate, was a section in ex¬actly the same condition—the same thin crack all around it filled with this.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carranaugh touched the gray pellet and replaced it in his wallet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Isn’t that enough? There have been at least twenty trained men, sup¬posedly experts, who have gone over that vault with fine-toothed combs in the past week, and not one of them discovered a smidgeon of evidence to show how the vault or the building- was entered. And here I—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s mighty fine work, Jim. I didn’t mean that it wasn’t. I simply was anxious to know what came next.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you mean what did I do next—I told Snedeker I thought I would have something interesting to report within forty-eight hours. He sniffed and mumbled something about ‘they all say that,’ but I didn’t mind his being skeptical. Can’t blame him for sniffing at the end of a week of nothing but prom¬ises without performances. Then I came here and put in the time, while waiting for you, in figuring out a work¬ing theory.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you got one?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sort of one. Remember, I’m not sure those plates are loose. I only think so. But I’m basing as much of a theory as I have on their being so.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then they must have tunneled un¬der the building after all—is that it ?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It looks that way. Something like that. But what I’m bothered about is the loose plate, if it is loose, in the safe deposit vault. Instead of making the proposition simpler, it complicates it. What on earth did they want to mon¬key round that vault for-—probably not enough valuables in the boxes to pay high class crooks for the taking, men who were figuring on more than a mil-lion. Can you dope that out? I can’t, yet.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe they made a mistake— opened up the wrong vault first and then went on to the right one.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe. That’s possible. But not probable. Expert cracksmen who could locate the center of the vaults at all wouldn’t make a mistake of over twenty feet in their point of attack. No, that isn’t the explanation. I’m sure it isn’t. There’s some other twist in the tangle, a better reason than that.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then maybe—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hold on a minute, Tom! An al¬most human idea is trying to bore its way into my brain and I’m afraid to frighten it away by talking. Sit still and pray!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peiperson smoked his pipe and was silent as directed while Carranaugh almost visibly labored in his effort to concentrate on the glimmer of thought that suddenly had occurred to him. Finally, slowly, his eyes brightened, his huge body seemed to bulk even more hugely, he breathed like a diver com¬ing to the surface as he whispered: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By-the-seven-gods - who - rule - the-seas, I believe I’ve got it! I believe— I believe I know where that million is lying this blessed minute and how it got there! I believe I could lay my hands on it in less than ten minutes’ walk from where we’re sitting! I be¬lieve—I believe—.” His voice trailed off into nothingness as he stared at the wall as if his eyes were piercing through and beyond it to the hiding place of the missing million. “Spring it, Jim! Spring it!” But Carranaugh insisted that they go and eat their long deferred dinner before he told his vision, declaring that he needed to piece it out in spots be¬fore telling even Tom. So it was not until be bad fed mightily that he ex¬plained his “almost human idea.” Then the two fell eagerly to discussing the pros and cons, the possibilities and their plans of activity for the morrow —a morrow that was fairly well begun when Jim caught a Madison street car for his houseboat on Lake Washington and Tom one going south for Mount Baker Park, where he knew that Mts. Tom would be waiting up for him even at that hour, so unholy for the home¬coming of a married man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-vii&quot;&gt;CHAPTER VII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At nine o’clock next morning, Peiperson appeared at the office of the city engineer and asked to be allowed to examine plats of the Pioneer Square district, new and old, the older the bet¬ter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was little that Tom could not get granted when he asked for it as he knew how to ask. For the next several hours he pored over the maps looking for a certain definite something that he felt convinced was in existence, whether the plats showed it or not. Luncheon and everything else were forgotten as he dug and delved through the dusty blue prints, tracings and brown paper drawings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as his finger followed line after line on the earliest city map he could find it came to rest upon two par¬allel series of small dashes enclosing the word “Abandoned.” Heaving a sigh of combined satisfaction and weariness, he borrowed a piece of tracing cloth and a pen from one of the draughtsmen and made a rapid but carefully accurate copy of the street and property lines in the district sur¬rounding the spot that had ended his quest and the contiguous waterfront and wharves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sectional map he then compared and checked with the latest official plat, noting the changes and corrections made by the city’s development and growth. Thanking the engineer who had assisted him he departed, trying to whistle and smoke at the same time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile Carranaugh had put in an equally busy morning at the Totem National going over the records of the safe-deposit department, making nu¬merous inquiries of the bank official directly in charge and generally, in the opinion of that official and of Daniels, making a pronounced and utterly use¬less nuisance of himself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Instead of going right out and catching the thieves and returning our money to us,” as Daniels phrased it to his fellow employee, who agreed whole¬heartedly, adding that “asking foolish and impertinent questions about re¬spectable customers who rented safe-deposit boxes” was not the way he would have set about catching bank burglars if he had been a detective, which, he was devoutly thankful to say, he was not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Little better than burglars them¬selves,” declared Daniels. “No wonder they talk about ‘setting a thief to catch a thief.’” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on in undertones during the interims between Carranaugh’s count¬less inquiries of who, why, when and whither about the men who held the keys to those boxes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally Carranaugh discovered the specific something fop which he had been looking as evidently as had Peiperson, made an entry consisting of three numbers in his note book, smiled con¬tentedly in self-appreciation that would have been no whit lessened had he overheard the opinions that had so recently been expressed about di i in genera] and one in particular, and betook himself to the appointed ren¬dezvous with Peiperson. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About six o’clock that evening Carranaugh and Peiperson, dressed in old clothes and rubber hip-boots, rowed out into the Bay in a boat, in which fishing tackle was prominently displayed and other equipment as carefully concealed. At nightfall they had not returned but the boat owner, knowing both in¬timately as fishermen and men, neither worried nor waited. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They would “get back when they returned” this safety-first-prophet de¬clared and was satisfied to let it go at that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-viii&quot;&gt;CHAPTER VIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was high tide and dark when Tom and Jim rowed in from the Bay, head¬ing for the lights of the West Seattle ferry slip. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They did not stop at any of the land¬ing-floats but pulled slowly along the face of the wharves until they came to an opening between the piles near the foot of Yesler Way. Here they shipped the oars, eased the boat through the gap and so beneath the wharf and, pull¬ing and pushing with their hands, con¬tinued eastward until they felt the bow bring up softly against the ooze a hun¬dred yards or so in from the dockline of Railroad Avenue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With large electric torches to light their way and using the oars for poling they slipped and slid still further through the liquid muck until they were stopped by comparatively solid ground. Here they tied the boat’s painter to a stringpiece and with grimaces of disgust stepped overboard, sinking at once almost to the tops of their hip-boots into what seemed to be nothing more than a semi-solidified smell. Stifling their gorge they made their way inland, Carranaugh flounder¬ing like a stranded whale spouting un¬seemly language, Peiperson, long, lean and lank, not having a much better time of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the one suffered on account of weight the other equaled by greater ease of penetration. But all things mun¬dane must have an end, and eventually Peiperson exclaimed in an excited whisper: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There it is! Dead ahead. Just where I said it would be!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It,” in the flare of their flashlights, was a six-foot circle of even deeper darkness than the surrounding gloom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another minute they had entered the old wooden-stave sewer pipe that had been indicated by the parallel dashes marked “Abandoned” on that map in the city engineer’s office. To their gratification and yet according to their hopeful expectations they found this ancient sewer-pipe not only in an excellent state of preservation, due to the thick cedar staves of which it had been constructed, but unchoked to a remarkable degree by the debris of years that normally would have been looked for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Chain!” called Carranaugh, a hun¬dred feet in the rear, as the surveyor’s steel hundred-foot tape tautened, giv¬ing the signal to indicate that another length of the “chain” had been meas-ured. And, as he came up with Peiper¬son, who pointed to the tally mark, “That makes five hundred.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guess we can thank our friends for this easy going,” remarked Tom, as he prepared to go on again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unh-hunh. Must ‘a’ been a nice job of house-cleaning,” puffed Jim, who very nearly filled even that six-foot pas¬sageway. “I’m glad the old sourdoughs who built this boulevard made it sizable’ enough for a. man to squeeze through, or I sure would have been up against it taking part in this expedition. We ought to be nearly there. Keep your eye peeled for signs of their work. Watch the ceiling.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About four hundred feet more, if my estimate of the distance was correct. Look out for a big snag here.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Chain” was called three more times and Peiperson had dragged out more than half the length of the tape again when Carranaugh heard a muffled shout from the darkness ahead, where he could just make out the flare of his friend’s torch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dropping his end of the tape, Jim plunged ahead at as near a run as he could achieve in the, for him, cramped quarters, until he joined Peiperson, who was pointing dramatically with his hand holding the torch at something over his head and with the other at something else evidently lying in the darkness at his feet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Was I right?” panted Carranaugh as he came up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Right as the seventh son of a sev¬enth son, you son of a gun of a prophet! Look!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carranaugh looked up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly above their heads was an opening, similar to what miners call a “raise,” roughly squared six feet by six, cut through the stave pipe and continu¬ing upward as far as the light of their torches penetrated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one side was the lower end of a crude but strong ladder, rising into the darkness. At their feet, upon a mix¬ture of mud, rotted planks and sawdust, broken concrete and general debris, lay several hand drills, short-handled sledges, picks, shovels, a hand pneumatic pump, what looked like a complicated variety of plumbers’ blowpipe, a head¬piece such as is used by electric welders, a V-shaped trough about five feet long and a foot deep made of some highly glazed material resembling porcelain, a broken electric torch, and odds and ends of tools—axes, saws, braces and bits, nails, a small iron pot for melting glue or lead, all the miscellany of a small workshop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our friends the Samuel Smiths evi¬dently knew what they wanted when they wanted it,” commented Peiperson. “And you’re a wiz for doping out their plan of campaign, Jim. My kindest regards.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carranaugh only grunted in reply as he heaved himself up the ladder, gin¬gerly testing each rung to see if it would bear a weight not usually required of such a makeshift. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well! I’ll be eternally and ever¬lastingly—” floated down to Peiperson from the regions above as he scrambled quickly upward. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He found Carranaugh standing on a small platform of heavy timbers, set solidly into the earth at either end. In the center of this there was raised an¬other box-shaped structure about five feet square, and upon this were set four jacks such as are used by contractors for raising and upholding buildings. The upper ends of the jacks, thrust through a space that had been filled with the reinforced concrete that extended from the hole in all directions, were resting against or, rather, were rested upon by a steep plate. And if any iden¬tification of that plate had been neces¬sary, it was supplied by a narrow streak on all four sides, outlined in dirty, steel-colored grease! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So this is what holds up that vault plate,” said Carranaugh, as he patted one of the jacks. “I wondered how they had managed that. Now let’s see if my other guess was as good as this one.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They descended the ladder, went some twenty feet deeper into the abandoned sewer, and then saw that Carranaugh had guessed right both times.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here a practical duplicate of the other “raise” and its several features led up to another similarly supported plate. They would only have to release the four jacks, lift out the plate section and raise themselves through the opening to be standing in the safe-deposit vault of the Totem National Bank. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, fearing the possibility of heart disease afflicting the guardian, who probably was standing no more than three inches above their heads, and for reasons not unconnected with their own safety should that extra vigilant watch¬man suddenly see their heads above the floor level of the vault, they reluctantly postponed making the spectacular en¬trance into those sacred and supposedly safe precincts that would have been at orice so easy and, to say the least, unex-pected. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two very tired and extremely dirty but almost hilariously elated fishermen tied up their boat in its appointed place some time after midnight and disap¬peared in the direction of the Alaska Club’s Turkish baths. In these sapo¬naceous quarters, as moist as those they recently had left, but gratefully clean, they luxuriated for a good part of the night. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-ix&quot;&gt;CHAPTER IX&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When U. P. Snedeker, president of the Totem National Bank, arrived at that institution shortly before ten o’clock the morning of the tenth day after the robbery he was in a very bad humor. j &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board of directors, as well as several gentlemen who were powers in the financial world and coincidently in the affairs of the Totem National, had seen fit, the day before, to treat him, U. P. Snedeker, as he often was in the habit of treating lesser employees of that bank. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a word, he had been “called upon the carpet”—the carpet of his own comfortable and handsomely furnished of¬fice, to speak literally as well as figura¬tively—and there also “called down “ He had been spoken to in very plain, rude words, words that were not minced and that hurt his self-love and pride, pointed words that also seriously threat¬ened to affect his almost equal love of pelf and position. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, Snedeker, U. P. Snedeker, presi¬dent and autocrat of his little realm, who daily was accustomed to making his power and personality felt by all with whom he came in contact in the bank or out, had been told in almost the same tone and terms he would have used to a mere bookkeeper that one more chance would be given for him to make good. Making good, in this case, signified the recovery of the lost million of the bank’s most liquid assets, a loss, it was inti¬mated more directly than diplomatically, which was due to his, Snedeker’s, failure to foresee and provide adequate safe¬guards of the funds entrusted to him as the controlling official of the bank. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If he failed to restore—”restore” was the word they used—the funds within the additional time allotted to him by the aforesaid powers his resignation would be accepted—without regrets. Not only without regrets, but, it was intimated, with the possibility of civil or criminal action. They handed it to him good, with no more regard for his feelings or the facts than he himself would have shown. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as has been said, U. P. Snedeker was in a very bad humor. He barked at the doorman, snapped at the receiving teller and almost bit Daniels. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was into this surcharged atmos¬phere, this mental and temperamental curtain of fire—and brimstone—that Jim Carranaugh entered a few minutes later. A very blithe and cocky Carra-naugh, radiating peace on earth and good-will toward all men, including even burglars and bank presidents, one may almost say particularly toward burglars and bank presidents, since it was to the happy combination of gentlemen pursu¬ing these more or less diverse activities that Carranaugh owed his present high spirits. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nor were these spirits in the least ironed out or even dampened by the scowl of the doorman, the snarl of the receiving teller or the snap of Daniels. No, not even by the excellent imitation of a savage and surly dog given by Snedeker. The Honorable James J. was above and beyond the reach of all such petty irritations, human or canine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good morning to you, Mr. Snede¬ker!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grunt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve a bit of news for you.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growl. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You remember I promised to report progress this morning.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grumble. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But first I want to have a little un¬derstanding with you.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The substance of Snedeker’s response, divested of its accompanying verbal adornment, was to the effect that Car¬ranaugh certainly would come to an un¬derstanding that would leave no room for doubt about the bank president’s opinion of all detectives in general and Carranaugh in particular. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the cyclone had passed, Carra¬naugh, unruffled by so much as a single hair, continued: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About that fifty thousand reward.” /It is too bad that Snedeker’s language at this part of the dialogue cannot be re¬ported verbatim, but the rules of public print forbid. If beauty consists of ar¬tistic expression, then Snedeker’s re¬marks were beautiful, however inde¬cently nude. But beyond a smile of appreciation for successful effort, Car¬ranaugh continued to be unimpressed, and unmoved from his line of thought and conversation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Will you pay it upon return of the money and securities, or must delivery be made of the thieves as well?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snedeker, with a banker’s sense of the all-important when actual cash is the subject under discussion, immediately stopped wasting perfectly good words and countered: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you found them?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The money or the thieves?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Both—either?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think I have.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Think! Think!’ I’m not paying you to think! I’m paying you to know!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Begging your pardon, Mr. Snedeker, but you’re not paying for either—yet. You are only promising to do so. And it is what that promise covers, or demands, that I want to know.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did I say ‘fifty’ thousand, Carra­naugh? Wasn’t ‘five’ the sum I men­tioned? Seems to me, as far as I can remember—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll have to remember a good deal farther than that, Mr. Snedeker, if you want me to recover that million for you! If you are trying to crawfish because you think maybe I have succeeded where all the others failed, if you are trying to Jew me down because .you think I’ll be lucky, and glad, to get even five—anything you choose to pay—well, all I have to say is that you have another think coming! If that’s the way you feel about it I’ll say good morning and you can go to—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tut, tut, Mr. Carranaugh, don’t allow yourself to get so excited and jump at unwarranted conclusions. Maybe it was fifty thousand, I said. Maybe it was.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No ‘maybe’ about it! Is it fifty?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you got them?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That depends, as I said before.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t fence with me, man! This is serious. Very serious. Much more serious than you can imagine.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not fencing with you. I am trying to do business. Fifty thousand dollars’ worth of business to mc—a million dollars’ worth to you. And if you’ll kindly cut out the cuss words and the condescension, drop the rough stuff and talk like a gentleman as well as a banker, maybe we can do that busi¬ness.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the devil do you mean? You impudent—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, very well!” said Carranaugh, rising to his feet and picking up his hat. “If you are going to start that again I’ll be on my way and see if Peter B. Far—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One syllable of that “power’s” name was enough, under the recent circum¬stances and Carranaugh’s implied intent, to bring Snedeker to at least an outward semblance of politeness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sit down, Mr. Carranaugh, sit down. I didn’t mean to be hasty—but you don’t know the load of responsi¬bility I am carrying, what a strain I’ve been under the past ten days. Sit down and tell me all about what you think you have discovered and I’ll try to re¬strain my natural impatience. Between my anxiety and the everlasting promises of tomorrow’ of the score or more men I’ve had working on this case, you should not blame me for being sick of your tribe—I mean of your incom¬petent competitors.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s all right, Mr. Snedeker. I understand. Only don’t class me with them or try to talk to me as you may to them. I’m apt to he fussy when I’m sworn at. And now, if you will answer my question, I will answer yours.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What question?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you pay that reward of fifty thousand dollars for the return of the million, or must the thieves be included in the delivery?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damn the thieves! That is, of course, you understand—we must do our duty to society, uphold law and order at whatever cost to ourselves, consider the public weal and the demands of justice, and—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then, I understand, the money and tin- securities will be enough?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you negotiated for their re¬turn—eh—that is, I mean can you de¬liver* them—if we don’t insist on ap¬prehending the—” I can. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can! You mean it? My dear Mr. Carranaugh! You don’t know what a load you are lifting from my heart! You surely—?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I surely can.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All of it?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every sou—less the fifty thousand.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You mean they—?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No. I mean me. If I turn over the whole thing to you, without a dollar or a bond missing, do I get the fifty thou¬sand?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snedeker’s eyes narrowed as he gazed straight into Carranaugh’s and Carranaugh’s eyes were blandly wide open as he gazed back. Snedeker sighed, cleared his throat twice as if something was sticking in his thorax, finally squeezed out: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You do.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Will you be good enough to put that on paper?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you doubt my—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not doubting anything. Merely a matter of form, of business procedure, of—shall we sat’?—ordinary banking precaution, Mr. Snedeker.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can you do it?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can lay your hands on that million in less than five minutes after you sign that promise to pay—or you needn’t pay.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snedeker wrote hastily for a few minutes, made the wholly illegible scrawl that passed for his signature and handed the paper to Carranaugh with an explosive: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There! Now show me!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carranaugh read the instrument, nodded in satisfaction with its provi¬sions, folded and placed it carefully in his wallet and the wallet in his inside vest pocket, and with a deliberation maddening to the banker, heaved him¬self to his feet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’ll just step this way, Mr. Snedeker.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading the banker into the general offices of the Totem National, where they immediately became the focal point of every eye in the place, Carranaugh stopped in front of the treasure vault from which the million had so mys¬teriously disappeared. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Open the door, please.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guardian of the door looked from the big man to the president and the latter, frankly mystified and curious, nodded. As they stepped inside the detective said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I first want to show you how this vault was entered and the money taken out. If I turned it over to you first I’m afraid you would lose your interest in this feature of my discoveries.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All right. Only hurry.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As had been said, Carranaugh would have made a good actor if he had not been a better detective, as his ensuing actions proved, nothing of their histrionic value being lost because his au¬dience was limited to one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With much the air of Macbeth in the “apparition scene” he advanced to the center of the vault, making an im¬pressive gesture with his arm calling Snedeker’s attention to the floor, upon which he tapped lightly with his foot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is permissible exaggeration to say that Snedeker’s eyes threatened to pop out of his head as, fascinated, they saw one of the floor plates, one of the three-inch chrome steel supposedly impreg¬nable floor plates, part company with its fellows and drop out of sight, to be re¬placed a moment later by the head and broad shoulders of a man who turned a very dirty but grinning face up to look into the banker’s own, remarking: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello, Jim. All O.K.?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wh — wh — wh — what?” gasped Snedeker. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is my partner, Thomas Peiperson, of the Seattle Advertising Service, Mr. Snedeker. Mr. Snedeker—Mr. Peiperson. We’ll explain all the details later. Just now you must be more in-terested in the money. Come on, Tom.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The banker nodded, having no words to express his feelings just then, and followed silently after Carranaugh and Peiperson as they led the way to the door of the safe-deposit vault. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It must be confessed, here and now, that for all his mystification, all his eagerness, Snedeker was not as nervous as his two outwardly calm but inwardly anxious guides, whose nerves were on a wire-edge. They had bet on a .long shot, were gambling to a large extent upon what they felt were probabilities beyond reasonable doubt, but still prob¬abilities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was just possible, for all the evi¬dence upon which their belief was based, for all the feasibility of their theory, for all their confidence in their deduc¬tions, that the thieves had not hidden the million where Carranaugh and Peiperson felt they must have hidden it. They might even be right in the place of concealment originally chosen but again there was the possibility that it no longer held the treasure, that it subsequently had been removed to a place of greater safety for the thieves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it was that there were three, in¬stead of only one, extremely nervous men who watched the vault attendant unlock with his masterkey boxes num¬bered 358-359-360. three of the largest boxes in the vault, the three boxes that had been rented by one Seth C. Seeley. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-x&quot;&gt;CHAPTER X&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime later, when the contents of the three boxes had been most care¬fully counted and checked, when every dollar and ounce of gold, every bond and security, every item of value down to the last sheet of government revenue stamps that had been missing were ac¬counted for, when that paper signed by Snedeker had been exchanged for a Totem National checking account made out to the joint credit of James Carranaugh and Thomas Peiperson, when Snedeker had telephoned to certain gentlemen in a tone of voice suggesting injured innocence triumphant over un¬deserved criticism, when Jim had told their story with such emendations and additions as his imagination suggested were called for by its proper presenta¬tion and to the due credit of one Peiper¬son and himself, when these and sun¬dry lesser matters had been attended to, a smiling and affable Snedeker asked of a smiling and equally courteous Carranaugh: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now that everything of importance has been attended to, suppose you gen¬tlemen go to lunch with me and later tell me how the trick was worked and how you are going to catch the thieves.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The luncheon today—with pleasure. The explanation next week—with equal pleasure. But the thieves, Mr. Sned¬eker—don’t you think it only fair to leave the glory of catching them to Chief Stein and his men ? Surely we should grant them that consideration, not usurp their special prerogatives. Mr. Peiper¬son and I are not common cops, man hunters, bloodhounds willing to sacrifice value for victims. We are simply, may I say, mathematicians who put two and two together for the benefit of the finan¬cial interests of the community. Of course we could catch the men responsi¬ble for this outrage on you and your bank if we wanted to stoop to the lower problems of our arithmetical hobby— but you hardly would expect us to do that, I am sure, any more than you would stoop to the practices of a pawn¬broker. I know you wouldn’t. Your own position at the head of your profes¬sion enables you to appreciate our stand¬ing and feelings at the head of ours. So we may call the case closed, the problem solved, may we not? Thank you.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With which, to Peiperson, deliciously ironical effrontery, and, to Snedeker, properly phrased and satisfactory end¬ing of what had been a very unpleasant experience which he would be glad to forget completely as soon as possible, Carranaugh rose to his feet and mutely signified his readiness to add several more superfluous pounds to his weight. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-xi&quot;&gt;CHAPTER XI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if Snedeker was so easily an¬swered a certain married woman in Seattle was not. She demanded full explanation of several features of the mystery that the bank president was content to consider unimportant if not irrelevant details. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then—the banker was a man and had recovered a lost million and a nearly lost place and prestige, while Mrs. Thomas Peiperson, though she had a proprietary interest in a certain fifty thousand dollars, still was a woman and a woman not disposed to forego her feminine and marital prerogatives. And as, moreover, she was the wife of a thoroughly home-broken and properly trained husband, her questions could not be so easily evaded, not even by the clever twistings of the tongues of that husband and their mutual intimate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an evening a week or so later, having “fed the brutes” according to the injunction of Mrs. Solomon, placed them in easy chairs before the big fire¬place with a supply of tobacco and glasses that tinkled enticingly, and curled herself up on the couch in an entirely graceful and receptive attitude of beautiful body and alert mind, she commanded: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now, begin. I know all about the seven Samuel Smiths stopping at the seven hotels, the six who went away and the one who—who stayed, how they stole and hid the money, and the wonderful work you two did finding it. What you are to tell me now is why and how the one was killed, how the money was taken after the six were gone and the seventh was dead, why they masqueraded that way when it was sure to attract attention, why they put the money in another vault of the same bank instead of taking it away with them, and—and all the rest of it. Go ahead. I’m listening.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guess it’s up to you, Jim. Perform for the lady,” said Peiperson. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dropping into a touch of the brogue that he sometimes affected when in cer¬tain moods Carranaugh grinned back, saying: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She’s your wife, not mine—sorra be! It’s too full I am of her dinner and good things to talk yet awhile. I’m too busy looking at her and thinkin’ what a fool for luck y’ are, Tom dear. Besides, I’ve gained another twenty pounds the past week and it’s on my conscience I must bant again, bad luck to the fat of me! Let me meditate in peace upon the last man’s meal I’ll have for many’s the day. Do you tell the girl. I’ll add a word or two here and there should you forget, or correct you if you don’t give me the credit that’s due me, egregious egotist that y’ are. Make him, Mary, there’s the darlin’.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Mary made him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, dear, it’ll do no harm to con¬fess in the bosom of our family that we only can guess at part of what you want to know, deduce other parts from cir¬cumstantial evidence, and be sure only of the little that remains. But if you will take the explanation as a mixture of all three and let it go at that without being too particular about which is which, here it is: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So that you will understand from the outset something that bothered us a good deal and very nearly threw us off the right track—as it was intended to do—I’ll begin in the middle with the fact that the body found in the vault was not one of the original seven Samuel Smiths at all, was not murdered or killed by them or anyone else, and had nothing to do with the looting of the bank except as a bit of ‘evidence’ plant¬ed in the vault to complicate the case and confuse the police. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The leader of the gang, the real Samuel Smith’ or whatever his name is, saw very clearly that an attempt, at least, would be made to trace the move¬ments of the seven men. He made the departing trails of his six assistants very easy to follow, once they had done their part of the heavy preliminary work in the old sewer. He figured that the police, finding six identical clues, would be so puzzled that they would simply begin to chase their tails. And even if they caught one or two of the six, they would still be beaten, for the money was still safe in the vault. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But. since he himself was compelled to remain in the city to carry out the actual robbery and then wait until it would be reasonably safe to take the swag out of town without being caught at railroad station or steamship dock by the plain-clothes men on guard, it was necessary that the seventh ‘mem¬ber’ also should be as easily accounted for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s where the ‘murdered’ man came in as part of the setting of the scene. He had, it is probable, been pro¬vided for in advance and held in readi¬ness for the silent but important part he played. It was no insuperable diffi¬culty for such a clever and resourceful crook as ‘Samuel Smith’ to secure from some other city a body of a man with a Vandyke beard and looking sufficiently like himself and the other six to pass muster—especially since the police and we ourselves were only too ready to jump blindly at conclusions. It really needed no more than a fair suggestion of a likeness, coupled with the duplicate clothes and belongings, to turn the trick and make us all think that the entire gang was accounted for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And we would have let it go at that and probably never dispelled the mys¬tery if it had not been for our sleepy friend here. Jim’s suspicions were aroused the first time he visited the morgue and examined the body. The wound in the back didn’t look just right to him as a basis for a burial certificate, and there was not nearly enough blood on the blade of the hunting knife to satisfy his demand for gore. He fussed around and made himself such a gen¬eral nuisance to the coroner and the coroner’s physician that, to get rid of his pestering, they agreed to perform an autopsy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They did. Jim was right. That wound in the back was not the cause of death. The knife had been driven into the body at least and probably more than forty-eight hours after the man had died of a hemorrhage of one of the large abdominal arteries, due to a ma¬lignant ulceration of the intestines. This was proved, not only by finding the very evident proof of the internal rupture, but also by the fact that all the blood in the body had drained into the abdominal cavity, where it had almost entirely coagulated. Also, there was no sign of bleeding in or about the region of the ‘wound.’ &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So much for so much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve just suggested the reason for their not taking the loot with them at once—every avenue of egress from the city would be watched for days after¬ward by the forces of the law. Well, then, what hiding place would be less likely to be suspected than the safe-de¬posit vault of the bank itself? Smith was evidently too experienced a crook to find any difficulty in getting hold of a master key. So he simply opened the boxes, took out his packages, emptied the rocks or old bricks that filled them into the sewer opening, and put in the gold, money and securities. Now he could come back, weeks or months after¬ward, take out his packages, and escape all suspicion. But Jim here doped it all out the moment he ran across the trail of the three boxes rented by ‘Seth C. Seeley’—who of course was none other than the gang leader himself— after he had discovered the second loose plate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you could have gone through that abandoned sewer with us—which your sensitive nose may be thankful you didn’t—and seen the amount of work it must have taken to clear it of the debris of years, to cut those holes up to the concrete foundation and then chip it away under both plates through several feet reinforced with steel rods, and finally to burn those extremely narrow cuts through three inches of super-hardened steel, you would have won¬dered that it had not taken seventy men instead of seven. They must have been at it for weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The ‘greasy dust’ was paraffin mixed with fine steel filings and served simply to fill and hide the cuts made in the plates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About the ‘masquerading,’ as you call it, at the hotels. I think some of that performance was just that and no more —a touch of melodramatic theatricalism put on for its own sake and to gratify the whimsical humor of ‘Samuel Smith,’ who, I imagine, is a bit of a farceur in his way. Of course he had a serious purpose also. His plan—which he car¬ried out exactly in every detail except the final disappearance with the million —called for the transference of the treasure from one vault to the other in a single night and by himself alone, after the plain departure of the six lesser crooks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This involved not only a number of hours of very hard work for him but also the running of the greatest degree of risk that had been taken. He planned. in the event of his being caught at any stage of the proceedings, except when he was actually handling the valuables, to be able to make all attempts at posi¬tive identification so ridiculous that no court would have held him on the evi¬dence submitted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He would have some thirty-odd reputable witnesses to swear that he was in seven places doing the same things at the same times—and so discredit any police testimony about his actions at any other time. If the one was impossi¬ble—the other would or might appear equally so. Or, at any rate, the chance was worth the effort—the chances plus the pure whimsical humor of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There you have the whole story.” “Do you mean to say that you are going to stop there, that that is all there is to it? Fiddle! It isn’t a bit as ex¬citing as I thought it was going to be. You’ve taken all the romance out of it. I want to know what became of ‘Samuel Smith’ and his six doubles or would you call it sextuples? What he did’ when he found you had opened those boxes instead of his—how he finally got away—and a whole lot of other things,” expostulated Mary Peiperson, pouting at her husband and the somnolent Carranaugh. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry, Sweetheart, but I’ve told you all I know.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there isn’t any dramatic end¬ing?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guess not. ‘Them’s the bare unin¬teresting facts’ in a nutshell—unless you want to call an interchange of ads dramatic.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ads? What ads? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One I wrote and one in reply from ‘Samuel Smith’.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That sounds a little encouraging.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks for the wild applause. I can quote them both from memory. Mine, published in all the large papers of the Northwest, ran: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To the Seven Who Were One and the One Who Was Seven, Greeting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks for your contribution to the&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;deserving charity that begins at the home of&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;C. and P.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And he replied in the same papers:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;C. and P.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You are welcome, since I was unable to contribute to the still more deserving charity nearer home that I had intended to benefit. Sorry not to be able to offer my congratulations in person but the first law of nature forbids. Possibly we shall meet at some later date. Tables have a way of turning. Au revoir.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Man Who Was Seven.&lt;/em&gt;” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-end&quot;&gt;The End&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-man-who-was%20seven/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-man-who-was%20seven/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Long Arm of God</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a rock-bound gulch, half-buried under the sands of summer, covered beneath ten feet of snow in winter, six skeletons lie, grinning mockingly. In the hollow skulls of two are smooth, round holes. In one a tiny, leaden pellet leaps and bumps with each heave and groan of the sun-kissed ice in spring. The whitened ribs of two are seamed and scarred as by a knife. Upon the sixth there is no mark. Nor comes there any answering rattle when some loathsome reptile, scurrying from its lair amongst the rocks and crevices, jars against the whitened shell that once encased as foul a brain as e’er polluted God’s green footstool. It lies far apart from the others, denied, even in death, the solace of their companionship.
It is of the tenant of that sixth grim remnant, gazing, hollow-eyed, toward the heavens it can never enter, that this story is written. The flesh that once covered his weather-bleached bones has long since been carried away by carrion birds; his malignant soul is now frying in hell—unless, by chance, the devil, fearing the corruption of his powers of darkness, has denied the spirit admittance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He mocked God and spit upon His Commandments. And the long arm of God reached out and found him—even in the chill, cold arctic hell where he had hidden himself away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lee was the first to die. They found him, a month after they had discovered that they were rich—cold and stiff, his face twisted into an indescribable grimace, as if he had died in awful agony. Yet there had been no outcry. Nor was there any mark upon his body to show how he had been struck down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The six of them—Lee, the profane; Halligan, the religious; Mason, the student; Wentworth, ill-tempered and moody; Kelly, the hot-blooded Celt; and good-natured, plodding, old Drew— were from the same Mid-Western town. , .They had grown up together, attended the same school, soldiered in the same squad. The same girl had driven them to the land of long winters to seek their fortune. And, smarting under the same misfortune, they had been drawn together, forgetting, for the time, their differences, sharing one another’s dangers, living out of a common purse, laughing at hardships—yet each praying that he might be the one upon whom Fortune’s smile would fall—buoyed up by the memory of a beautiful girl far, far from their adopted home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a fashion, they were happy. They were filled with primitive vigor and pulsing with life. They lived constant romances and did not know it. For such is the way of the far countries. And the lure of the North had gripped their heartstrings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had been prospecting, without results, all summer, when they chanced upon the unmapped, blind canyon which was destined to he their burial place. Following the noisy little creek up the gulch to the spot where it bubbled from * the side of the rocky wall which blocked the farther end of the canyon, between two gray, grim mountains, they decided to “hole in” for the winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were signs of gold everywhere. A cabin, old and weatherbeaten—one of the unsolved mysteries of the ever-mysterious North—stood ready for their occupancy with a small amount of repairing. Near by were a dozen mounds —grim reminders of a tragic past. In the cabin were bags filled with nuggets, their coverings rotted away. The whole place breathed of mystery—of mystery and treasure untold. Wood was plentiful and game was abundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan and Lee were sent back for supplies. The others divided their time between prospecting the gulch and putting in shape their shack —a four-roomed affair—for they intended spending the winter in comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks after the return of the two,-the partners awoke to the realization that they were rich. Before they could even estimate the extent of their find winter arrived, with its long, cold nights, burying the old cabin almost to the eaves under a mass of snow which filled the gulch, tying them up effectually for the remainder of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no stronger test of friendship than the placing of strong, vigorous men for several long, weary months in enforced confinement. With little to do save eat and sleep, forced to gaze at each other day after day, they are apt to fall into a physical lethargy which eventually creates a nervous tension like nothing else in the world. Petty quarrels become serious “matters. Molehills are magnified into mountains. They grow to hate the sight of each other— to become suspicious of what, under other circumstances, would not be noticed. And, when each looks upon his companions as his rivals for the hand of a beautiful woman, hell is bound to break loose sooner or later. It is as inevitable as fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they found the grisly horror that was Lee, lying stark and stiff in his bunk, gazing, glassy-eyed, toward the ceiling, there was no thought of foul play. It was Halligan who, in straightening out the cold, clinched fingers, discovered the tiny thread of gray wool in the doubled-up fist and called the attention of the others to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wentworth was the owner of the only gray shirt in the camp. The others wore khaki or blue. It had been a cold night and he had slept in it. Instantly all eyes were turned upon him, although no word was spoken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned upon his silent accusers, his lips drawn back in a wolfish snarl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damn it! If you think I done it, say so!” he growled. “If I killed him, how did I do it—and when ? You, Halligan, slept in the same room with us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan shook his head sadly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When I went to bed, the two of you, and Kelly, were soldering that hole in the old coffee-pot. I went to sleep before either of you turned in.”
Kelly looked at Halligan angrily, then cast a sympathetic glance at Wentworth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry to say, boys, that I ‘hit the hay’ before the other two. I wish now that I hadn’t, because I’m confident that if Lee was killed—and I don’t think that he was—it wasn’t Wentworth that done it. He’s not that stripe. In fact.” he hastened on, “none of the bunch is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wentworth snorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Keep your blasted sympathy to yourself! I don’t want it!” he growled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan shook his head mournfully.
“It’s the visitation of God upon Lee for his blasphemy,” he muttered. “I warned him against it many a time— poor boy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They sat around all day discussing their-companion’s sudden taking away— all but Wentworth. He sat alone in a corner, silently nursing his grievances. They had searched the body; there was not a mark upon it. The other four were loud in their statements that Lee must have died a natural death. But there was a feeling of coldness—an indescribable something that cast a pall over them all—a feeling toward their once-trusted comrade—a feeling that the long, lonely days of idleness and soundless nights of the past now magnified into an unspoken suspicion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late in the afternoon they carried Lee’s body up the gulch a few yards and buried it in a shallow grave dug in the ice .and snow, where it would have to lie until spring opened up again. The ground was frozen too hard to dig a grave being covered by a dozen feet of hard-packed snow and ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only Wentworth remained away from the simple funeral, sitting glumly by himself inside the cabin while Halligan mumbled, brokenly, as much as he could remember of the burial service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late when they retired that night. All but Wentworth. He refused to eat any supper, throwing himself onto his bunk immediately after the others had finished eating, where he lay, scowling, his eyes staring into vacancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;III&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They slept fitfully. It was nearly morning when they were awakened by the sharp explosion of a gun. They leaped to their feet and one of them struck a match and lighted a, flickering tallow candle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wentworth lay dead in his blankets. Over him hung a pall of acrid smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He lay upon his back, a bullet hole in his temple, his lips drawn back in the same wolfish snarl he had worn during the day. On the floor beside him, where it had dropped from his nerveless hand, lay his revolver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next morning they buried him in the snow beside the man who they were now sure had been his victim. And once more it was Halligan who was called upon to say a prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again he repeated his warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can’t you see, boys,” he mourned, “that the Lord visited his wrath upon Wentworth for his sins—just as he did upon Lee. A man’s evil deeds will find him out. It’s a warning for you all to repent before it’s too late.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no work done that day. Even the dishes were allowed to go greasy and unwashed while they discussed again and again the various phases of the second tragedy that had befallen their little community. Wentworth had never been popular with the others, his moroseness and general tone of surly indifference to everything keeping him from being the general favorite that the profane but good-natured Lee had been. Yet it was hard to believe that he had stooped to murder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, it was Halligan, the born leader, who aroused them from their apathy. Putting the others to cleaning up the dishes, he cooked a hasty supper and compelled the three to eat with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s no use getting the doldrums,” he admonished them. “They’re dead, and sitting around mooning won’t bring ‘em back. The Lord giveth and the Lord taketh away. Of course, it’s up to us to see that their heirs get their share of the mine after we’ve taken our wages out for working it. When we’ve fed and cleaned up the shack we’ll have a game of cards and turn in early. I, for one, am sleepy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So were they all, for, within an hour after they had eaten, the four of them were yawning vigorously. They crawled into their bunks, Halligan, who refused to sleep in the room where Lee and Wentworth had met their deaths, climbing into a spare bunk with the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mason was the first to awaken next morning. He shouted for the others as he leaped out of his blankets and crawled into his clothes. Replenishing the logs in the fireplace in the living-room, he again yelled at the other three and turned his attention to breakfast.
A second later a loud cry from Kelly brought Halligan to his feet, while Mason ran in from the outer room.
For Drew lay dead in his bunk. Between his ribs, buried to the hilt, was a hunting-knife. And it was Mason’s knife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly carefully drew the knife from the wound and looked at the initials carved on the handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, ‘twas you, after all, was it, you skunk?” he snarled at Mason. “You with your damned sneaking ways and your smooth, oily manner, eh? Though why you were fool enough to leave your knife stickin’ in him is what I can’t understand. Scared away, were you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mason stepped back a pace, a look of amazement on his proud face. “I swear by the ever-living God, boys, that I am innocent!” he declared. “Why would I kill Drew?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why—yes, why ?” snorted Kelly, his eyes glittering. “For the same reason that you killed Lee and threw the blame for it onto poor Wentworth, damn your soul! I suppose that Halligan and I were to be the next, eh ?” he went on. i tli us out of the way you’d be a rich man. And then you could go back and marry Cora Hunter. Oh, I’m no fool.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan, sitting on the edge of his bunk putting on his moccasins, said nothing. Kelly, his Celtic temper leaping to the surface, was intensely angry. Mason, too, was a man of hot passions, although he held them under better restraint than did the Irishman. He took a half-step toward his accuser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kelly—and Halligan,” he began in a level voice, “I didn’t kill Drew, nor had I a hand in the death of Lee. It’s just as much of a mystery to me how my knife got there as it is to you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“‘Tis no mystery to me,” snapped Kelly. “You put it there, you cur.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re a damned liar!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly leaped upon him, the knife he still held in his hand upraised. Mason’s fist met him half-way, striking him squarely in the face, but failing to stop his rush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a lurid oath the burly Irishman jabbed the weapon into the other’s side half a dozen times. With his bare fists Mason fought the other as best he could for a second or two. His fingers clutched weakly about his antagonist’s windpipe. He struggled blindly for a second, fumbling feebly for a hold. Then his knees doubled under him and, with a dull moan, he sank to the floor at Kelly’s feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a sign of undue haste, Halligan buckled his belt and holster about his waist. Coolly he unbuttoned the holster and drew the gun. He cocked the weapon and, with his finger on the trigger, waited for the others to settle their argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you get him?” he asked, as Kelly stepped back and wiped the blood from his streaming nose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, an’ I’m damned glad of it— the swine!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before he could turn around, Halligan placed the muzzle of his gun against the back of the Irishman’s head and pulled the trigger. A dazed expression crept over Kelly’s face. The knife dropped from his hand. Then he fell in a heap across the body of his late antagonist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan replaced the weapon in its holster and felt of the Irishman’s heart. Assuring himself that it had ceased to beat, he raised his eyes to Mason, who was staring at him dazedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You saved my life, Halligan,” the wounded man muttered thickly; “but you took so long doing it that he got me anyway. Much obliged;—just—same.” Halligan grinned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I did, I’m sorry,” he remarked, cheerfully. “ ‘Cause then I’ll have to finish you myself. It wouldn’t do for you to live, you see, because you know too much. And, besides, I want everything for myself—the girl and the money both.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dying man looked at him curiously. “You don’t mean that it was you, Halligan? Great God! And I never suspected!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan sat down on the edge of his bunk and laughed good-humoredly as he unbuckled his gun and threw it across the foot of the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t mind telling you about it,” he said quietly, “because you’ll soon be where you can never tell.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He rolled a cigarette and, lighting it, inhaled a whiff before he continued: “You see, Mason, I figured out long ago that as soon as we struck it rich— and I felt sure that we would sooner or later—it would be a survival of the fittest. I knew that there was no chance for any of us with Cora until we had money. She’s a selfish little devil, but she’s worth fighting for. And, with all of us rich, we would be just where we started. But now it’ll be me alone— just me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When we struck pay here, you remember it was me that suggested putting in here for the winter. I knew that it would be easy for me to plant the seed of suspicion in all of you, for, deep down in your hearts, you all felt as I did and each one of you suspected the other. And you were as jealous as a bunch of chorus girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wentworth killed Lee all right. I watched him do it from the other room, where I was supposed to be asleep. I suggested the idea of it to him without him knowing it several days before. He and I were doing a job of soldering and I told him a story I got from my grandmother—about a man who had murdered his wife by pouring a drop of hot lead in her ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After Kelly turned in that night, Lee and Wentworth sat up soldering, you remember. Finally Lee dropped off to sleep with his head on the table. It was too good an opportunity for Wentworth to miss—for he hated Lee’s guts—so he drops a bit of the hot solder into Lee’s ear. He died without a struggle, as I knew he would—for the infernal stuff paralyzes every faculty. Afterward Wentworth took off his boots and sneaked in to see if we were asleep. Finding that we were, he carried Lee in and laid him on his bunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You remember how Wentworth tore his shirt on a nail there by the door? I recollected that there was a scrap of wool banging onto it. When Wentworth went back into the other room to put away his tools, I jumped out, took the little piece of wool from the nail and got it into Lee’s clenched fingers and jumped back into bed before Wentworth returned. Pretty smooth, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wentworth couldn’t stand the gaff. He imagined that I knew that he had killed Lee, so he killed himself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mason groaned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I killed Wentworth!” he blurted out. “You told me that he had—that he^-he —about what he done to—to Cora. I saw that this was a good opportunity to get rid of him and let you fellows think he had done it himself.” You put me up to it, you devil!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan laughed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So it was you, after all, eh?” he chuckled. “I knew that you had swallowed my little story, but I’ll confess that I didn’t think you would get busy so quick.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But the letter you showed me from her—from Cora?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan chuckled again. “Mason, I don’t mind telling you that when I went after supplies with Lee I fixed up five letters, all identical except the names. I put one of your names in each letter. I showed each one of you a different letter, playing each one of you against the other. That’s why Kelly knifed you. He didn’t care a cuss for Drew—he was itching for an opportunity to get you. See? I stuck Drew myself, using your knife to throw suspicion on you, knowing that it would start the Irishman. Where I miscalculated was in thinking that you’d be armed. I didn’t want to stain my own hands with murder any more than I had to. I put some dope in all of your grub last night when I got supper so that I could pull off the stunt without arousing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That idea of mine of playing each one of you against the other was pretty slick, wasn’t it? No one knows of the existence of this blind gulch here. I’ll have a pretty good nest egg, and, after I marry Cora, I can always take a run back here for more if I need it. Of course, I’ll bury all of you fellows nice and shipshape and I’ll tell them back home about our separating and each going in a different direction. Oh, I’ve got a good yarn cooked up, all right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wounded man glared at him malignantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damn you!” he cried. “God’s long arm will get you yet—even out here in the ice and snow of this God-forsaken country.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan smiled. “God? Bah! If I’d believed in such foolishness I’d never won out over the rest of you. But I made you think I did—and that’s how I got the best of you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;V&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He arose and stretched himself. Then, seizing the dead man, he dragged his victim out of doors and buried him alongside of the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mason watched him at his work with glaring eyes. Then, as he left the room, the wounded man dragged himself across the few feet that separated him from the bunk. Carefully, every movement filled with pain, he reached up and took the gun. He tried to lift himself to his feet and felt himself going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“O God,” he murmured, “help me— help me—get him—don’t let him get— away with it. Help me for Cora’s sake.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He succeeded in getting the weapon cocked—in hiding it inside his trousers pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His jaw dropped and, with a convulsive twitch, he died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halligan finished burying Kelly and returned to the cabin for warmth. Replenishing the fire, he entered the other room and found Mason dead. Throwing him across his shoulder, he staggered out into the gulch again and laid him on the snow crust while he hastily scooped another shallow grave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He bent over the body to roll it into the hole. As he did so there was a flash and a report. The bullet swept across his lids, searing them with its heat. His eyes were filled with the powder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blinded, sobbing with his misery, he tried to grope his way back to the cabin. He lost his sense of direction. He stumbled and fell, arose and stumbled again. His snowshoes dropped from his feet. Too miserable to care, he tried to go on without them. He broke through the crust to his waist. On and on he floundered his way, whimpering with pain—chilled to the marrow—thinking to reach the cabin, but ever getting farther from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, exhausted, blinded, freezing, he fell into the stupor, which marks the beginning of the end in the Land of Eternal Snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sudden cold, grasping hold of the dead body of Mason, had hastened rigor mortis. The dead fingers, stiffening suddenly, had tightened about the trigger of the hidden revolver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the long arm of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE END&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-long-arm-of-god/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-long-arm-of-god/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Choice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;He hesitatingly walked up the broad stone steps. He was not yet used to the silent dignity of the hospital atmosphere. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside he took off his soft hat, crushed it in his hand, and instinctively softened his footfalls as he stepped to the information desk. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mrs.—el—Follis?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl silently plugged in the switchboard. A question, an answer: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Corridor B, room 8. They are waiting for you,” she said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Softly, almost on tiptoe, he walked down the long corridor, passing a nurse in the light blue, white trimmed, uniform distinctive of the hospital, turned to the right, and lightly tapped at a door on which the figure “8” appeared. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nurse opened the door, looked at him, turned and beckoned to someone in the room. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A physician, young, alert, came to the door, glanced at him a moment, came out and closed the door behind him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man before him nervously moistened his lips. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physician looked at him keenly. The man’s eyes returned the look questioningly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The time’s almost here,” said the physician. “It’s serious—the mother, or the baby. I’ve told her. She says to speak to you.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lightning expression passed over the man’s face. The physician’s boring gaze noted, but did not fathom it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“May I see her?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes—but only for a minute.” The physician turned and opened the door. The man advanced haltingly in the semi-darkness to the bedside. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“John!” and two weak arms reached up and clasped him around the neck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The doctor says—” her voice choked “the doctor says,” she whispered in weak tones in his ear, “that it is baby— or me.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A flash of pain winced her face, and she paused as it took her breath. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a moment: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told him I’d leave it to you,” she whispered as it passed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My brave girl! My brave girl! I want you—of course I want you,” he answered, low voiced, but vibrant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A look of ineffable joy came over her face. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He wants me!” she said feebly, bright-eyed, joy-flushed, to the physician standing at the bedside. “He’s come back at last—and he wants me!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spasm of pain convulsed her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physician leaned over quickly, and turned to the table of instruments at his side. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse gently took the man’s arm and led him to the door. Even in her pain the woman’s eyes lovingly followed him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door closed. A moment passed. It opened again, and the man’s head appeared inside. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Doctor!” he whispered softly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physician turned, looked, walked to the door. The man beckoned silently, and the physician went outside, closing the door quietly behind him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well?” he questioned. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Save the baby,” the man replied. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physician stared at him . . . turned and re-entered the room.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-choice/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/the-choice/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fingers from the Grave</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tom Grimstead was not looking for a “story” when he decided to spend a night in the haunted Carey house. As a newspaperman, he had frequently exposed many bogus mediums and spiritualists, but the accounts of those who had spent, or rather tried to spend, a night in the Carey house seemed so authentic and honest that Grimstead, who was enjoying his vacation in the quaint New England town of Sedley, longed to experience some of the thrills that had come to these narrators. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was a presence in the house,” quavered Martin Stacy, who had once spent part of a night there. “I—I felt it!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Could you see it?” asked Grimstead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin shuddered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” he whispered, “but I knew it was there—whatever it was. If anyone sneaked into your room when you were reading, without making any noise, you would feel they were there even if you hadn’t seen ‘em—wouldn’t you?” Grimstead nodded. “Well, it was that same sort of feeling that came over me in Mrs. Carey’s bedroom.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Stacy’s story was similar to the others. They had all felt a sinister presence in Mrs. Carey’s room and the feeling had always been followed by senseless, unreasoning terror that made them flee into the night. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Carey tragedy had been the grimmest that had ever occurred in the town of Sedley. Twenty years before, Weldon Carey had brought his bride to the old Carey house, which had been built by a colonial Carey and inhabited by Careys ever since. Selma Carey was beautiful and vivacious and she appeared to be as madly in love with the old house and its colonial traditions as she was with its master. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the tragedy! Young Mrs. Carey was found murdered one morning—strangled to death—and her husband told incoherently how two burglars had broken into the place at midnight. One of them had throttled Mrs. Carey and the other was threatening him with a revolver, when some noise frightened them away. The countryside was searched for the two men, but they were never apprehended and the verdict of the coroner’s jury was that Mrs. Carey had come to her death “at the hands of a person or persons unknown.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carey seemed heart-broken after the tragedy, and finally, not succeeding in selling the old house, he left it in charge of a caretaker and went abroad to live In all these intervening years he had never returned to his birthplace, nor could anyone be induced to rent the place. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Grimstead thought as he stood in front of the Carey mansion at dusk one September afternoon that he had never seen a more repellent-looking house. There was something indescribably repugnant about it, as if one were contemplating the corpse of a house. Horror surrounded it like a nimbus, and Grimstead’s first impulse was to walk hastily away. But shaking off the feeling of dread that had settled upon him like an incubus, he resolutely walked up the weed-encumbered” walk that led to the front door, armed with a key that he had experienced no difficulty in securing from a cynical real-estate agent, who promptly offered to wager that he would not stay the night out—a wager that Grimstead as promptly accepted. He carried a handbag that contained a supply of sandwiches, a small automatic, half a dozen fat candles, a flashlight and two volumes of Poe’s grisliest short stories. He ironically thought of these as his “ghost props.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, stout-nerved as he was, Grim-stead shrank back instinctively as the front door slammed shut, leaving him in impenetrable darkness. This instantaneous plunge into blackness was sudden enough to daunt anyone, and for a second time that afternoon Grimstead was tempted to abandon his ghost quest. Then he reflected that thrills were what he had come for, and he was disgusted at the realization that he was allowing his subconscious self to be affected by the stories he had heard. If he were really a skeptic, as he had always prided himself on being, he was on the verge of the most interesting adventure of his none-too-dull life. So he opened his handbag by touch alone, turned on his flashlight and took stock of his surroundings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was in an old-fashioned living room at the far end of which was a huge open fireplace. In front of him a fine specimen of colonial architecture in the shape of an imposing staircase pointed the way to adventure on the second floor. The large room was fully furnished, but a smell of decay and mildew assailed Grimstead’s nostrils. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere was heavy and fetid : odors of bygone days seemed to meet and commingle, and the air held a penetrating chill. Something soft brushed his face in the semi-gloom and he started back involuntarily and then laughed nervously. It was a death’s-head moth and the creature settled upon the back of a large upholstered chair, its wings spread wide, shivering as the bright ray from the flashlight illumined its ghastly markings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a little shiver that was not entirely due to the chill of the place, Grimstead started up the stairs in search of Mrs. Carey’s bedroom, which, he had been told, was the front room at the left of the upper hallway. But first he explored the other rooms, finding them all furnished but reeking with desolation and decay. Time had wrought sad havoc upon objects of inestimable value to the collector of colonial antiques. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grimstead now turned the handle of the door that led into the dead woman’s bedchamber and found himself in an ancient boudoir about which still clung an elusive odor of mignonette and lavender. Against one side of the wall was an antique dressing table, but the surface of the long mirror, which had in bygone days often reflected the fair image of Selma Carey, was now opaque, blurred over by the film of years. Near the dresser was a four-poster bed covered with a yellowed counterpane, and two pillows were in place at its head. It was hard to believe that no one had slept there for twenty years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the exception of the dust that covered everything, and a dank smell, the room and its furnishings appeared to have been left as they were on the day of the tragedy and Grimstead found himself glancing from time to time at the door of the dressing-room, which was about ten feet from the bed, as if he expected a charming figure in deshabille to come romping into the room at any moment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So acute was this impression that he strode across the room and threw open the door of the dressing room, peering curiously within. It contained an old-fashioned tin bathtub, the paint from which was chipped off here and there, giving it a dismal look of dilapidation. On a rusty metal towel-rack hung a rotting hath towel, and from a hook in the wall was suspended a mildewed dressing gown that had once been lavender-colored. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a look of infinite pity, Grim-stead closed the door softly behind him, his vivid imagination conjuring up the picture of a lovely woman with golden hair cascading to her waist, humming a gay little tune as she prepared for her bath. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He now set the stage for his lonely vigil. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lighting one of his fat candles, he placed it upon the dusty dresser in such a position that its flame illumined the bed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he stuck another above the fireplace on the white marble mantelpiece. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing up a small dressing table, he placed his third candle upon that and then he dusted off a comfortable Morris chair with wide arms and placed it where he could command a view of the entire room. The dressing table was at his left, within easy reaching distance, and on this he placed his sandwiches, his automatic and his volumes of Poe &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfied with these strategic arrangements, he lit his pipe, sank into the big chair and was soon immersed in “The Fall of the House of Usher,” which he had decided was the proper yarn for the time, the place and the man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was so silent in the house that the scampering of mice in the wainscoting sounded as loud as the romping of Newfoundland dogs. Every now and then one of them would squeal as if it were being murdered, and whenever this happened1 Grimstead would pause in his reading and look up with a startled tenseness, expecting to see—he knew not what. The wind was rising and it howled and moaned like a tortured spirit striving with futile hands to force an entrance through the rotting eaves of the ancient house. It was an eerie sound and Grimstead found himself forced to exert all his will power in order to concentrate upon the harrowing tale that he was reading. He felt like a spectator awaiting the climax to a particularly dramatic scene in a melodrama. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There came a lull in the wind and the mice suddenly ceased to scamper as if at a signal from a master mouse. The old house appeared to be waiting in suspense^—holding its breath. Grimstead had reached the point in his story where the sound of muffled blows from the vault was reverberating through the ill-fated house of Usher. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Madman,” he read, “I tell you—” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked up quickly. The dying down of the wind and the cessation of the scamperings in the wainscoting made the room feel as dead as stagnant water looks. But it was not the nerve-racking stillness that had galvanized Grimstead into alert attention. It was the unalterable conviction that someone or something was lurking near him. Reaching stealthily for the automatic, he glanced keenly around the room. Certainly he was the only living soul there! But— &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door of the dressing room was slowly opening! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grimstead stared incredulously at the widening aperture. He had thoroughly inspected the room less than half an hour before and no living creature could have been concealed there. Nor was there any other door to the room. The thing was impossible—yet it was happening before his eyes! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wider, wider the door opened, and then, as Grimstead held his breath in suspense, something stepped into the room. He could not see it but he felt it, and an icy wind suddenly stirred the roots of his hair at the realization that he was no longer alone. He heard the ghostly sound of footsteps crossing the room and then the candle on the dresser suddenly wavered as if a passing breeze had slightly stirred it. As the paralyzed newspaperman gazed wide-eyed from his chair, there came from the dresser the unmistakable sound of hairpins tinkling down into a celluloid tray. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking that an over-vivid imagination was playing him tricks, Grimstead, by a tremendous effort of will, sat erect in his chair and was about to spring to his feet, when an amazing thing stupefied him once more into inaction. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ghostly footsteps crossed the carpet once more, like the soft brushing of unseen wings, and Grimstead saw the bed suddenly sag—as if a body were lying there—and then one of the pillows became indented—as if a head were resting there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something invisible was reclining upon the bed! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this incredible fact percolated through Grimstead’s understanding, blind panic assailed him. Only one thing, he confessed afterward, prevented him from becoming a gibbering idiot. That was his discovery that the door leading into the dressing room, which was wide open after his visitant had entered, was now tightly closed. This tended to convince him that the entire episode was an hallucination due to overwrought nerves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, he sprang to his feet, determined to probe the mystery to its depths, when a sound smote upon his ears that stiffened him in his tracks and made him snatch the automatic hurriedly from the table. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone was coming up the stairs! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He heard the sound of shuffling, reluctant footsteps, as if the person, thing or whatever it was, were disinclined to make the ascent. Slower and more hesitant became these ominous footsteps, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and Grimstead, now utterly unnerved, gripped the automatic frantically and turned a white face in the direction of the bedroom door, not knowing what to expect. But he felt convinced that if this door opened as the other had done and no tangible thing entered he should scream like an hysterical woman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unwilling footsteps had now reached the landing outside the door and came to a halt there, as if the intruder were listening. This wait seemed interminable to the crouching newspaperman who stood immovably by the table, his automatic aimed straight at the door. Finally there was a shuffle of feet and then a hand turned the knob. Slowly the door opened. # &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hands up,” cried Grimstead hoarsely, “or I’ll shoot.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the devil?” growled a surprised voice, and Grimstead emitted a great sigh of relief. At least it was a human being! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A heavily built, bearded man about fifty years old, a stranger to Grimstead, walked slowly into the room, first glancing around fearfully before allowing his gaze to rest upon Grimstead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now then,” he said coldly, “who are you and what are you doing in this house?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just what I was going to ask you,” grinned Grimstead, his self-possession now fully restored. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am—” began the stranger—and then came the crowning horror of that memorable evening. The man’s voice suddenly broke and his tanned face turned livid with fear. He was staring with a look of indescribable terror at the bed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s that? Who’s there?” he whispered in high-pitched, terror-laden accents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why—what—” stammered Grimstead and then froze into the gaping figure of a man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The indentations in the bed and pillow slowly straightened out like a flat automobile tire when the air rushes in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once more Grimstead heard those ghostly footsteps and then the bearded man shrieked like a demon in hell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Selma, for God’s sake, don’t!” he * gasped. “I didn’t mean to do it! I swear I didn’t mean to do it!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He staggered back, fumbling at his throat and gasping for breath. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Take your hands away!” he panted. “My God, you are throttling me!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His voice died out in a choking gurgle and he staggered wildly around the room, pulling desperately at his throat as if trying to unloosen the clutch of hands. Grimstead took hold of the struggling figure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You are mad!” he cried. “There is no one here!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stranger did not seem to hear. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His eyes were rolling in his head and his face was turning a mottled purple. Up and down the room he .threshed in agony, trying vainly to break the deadly hold that was apparently fastened upon his windpipe with the grip of a maddened bulldog. It was a horrible sight and Grimstead could do nothing but follow the agonized man, who seemed destitute of all reason. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end came quickly! Suddenly there was a rattling sound in the man’s throat and then he sank slowly to his knees and toppled forward on his face. Once more the sound of invisible footsteps and Grimstead looked up from the dead body in time to see the door of the dressing-room open quickly and close. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he lost all control over his twitching nerves and ran shrieking out of the room, down the stairs and out into the fresh sweetness of the September night, staggering like a drunken man, his brain reeling from the horrors of that fetid bedroom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ill &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sight of the familiar street and the feel of the wind blowing in his face partially restored his faculties to normal, but he was trembling like a drug fiend as he entered Dr. Stoughton’s office and his speech was so incoherent that the amazed physician was convinced that he was either intoxicated or insane. But as the spell of the horror wore away and Grimstead began to talk more rationally Dr. Stoughton realized that this was no ordinary case and that Grimstead was neither intoxicated nor insane. He was that most pathetic of all objects— a strong man suffering from overwhelming fright. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Stoughton had been the Carey physician and was for many years Weldon Carey’s closest friend. So it was with a very grave face that he went back to the house with Grimstead, accompanied by “Mort” Farley, an official who facetiously called himself Sedley’s “chief of police.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was with a strong shudder that Grimstead entered the house that had shattered his skepticism to bits, and followed the two men upstairs. Everything in the bedroom was just as he had left it. His candles were still burning and his automatic lay where it had fallen from his nerveless hand. In the center of the room was a huddled heap that had once been a man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hm! This looks bad!” ejaculated Dr. Stoughton as he bent above the prostrate figure. He turned the body over and the face peered up at him, distorted and black as a charred log. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My God, it’s Weldon Carey!” he shouted, drawing back from the corpse in sudden horror. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do you know?” asked Farley in awestruck tones. “It has been twenty years—and this man wears a beard.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Stoughton lifted the man’s limp left hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can tell by this amethyst ring on -the little finger,” he explained. “It was given to him by his mother and he has always worn it on that finger, as it was too small to fit on any of the others.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What do you think caused his death, Doctor?” asked Grimstead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was a sudden rush of blood to his head,” said Dr. Stoughton, “caused by a tremendous shock of some sort.” Then, after a pause: “It couldn’t have been anything else. There are no marks on his throat,” and he looked challengingly at the newspaperman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I only know what I know,” replied Grimstead, and he told the whole story again for Farley’s benefit, not omitting the slightest detail. When he had finished, the police official looked doubtfully at Dr. Stoughton. This sort of a case was outside of his own ken. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Frankly, I am puzzled over all this,” began the physician, looking more closely at the face of the dead man. “It is very evident that— Hello!” he broke off abruptly. “This is devilish queer, I must say!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a small magnifying glass from his bag, he bent over the body and examined the throat carefully. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the most extraordinary thing that has ever come within my medical knowledge,” he said gravely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is it?” asked his companion curiously. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When I first looked at Carey,” explained the physician, “there were no marks whatever upon his throat. It was strangely white in contrast with his blackened face. But now look!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He handed the glass to Grimstead. The newspaperman looked, started, and then looked again. Without a word, he &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;handed the glass to Farley, who looked through it long and hard. Then he whistled softly. “ &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Finger prints!” he said laconically. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Exactly,” agreed Dr. Stoughton. ‘They have come out on the skin like a rash. Carey’s throat looked like an undeveloped negative when I first looked at it. But now, through some queer phenomenon, it has been ‘developed.’” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little silence followed his words. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you, perhaps, notice anything else when you looked through the glass?” continued Dr. Stoughton. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What, for instance?” asked Grimstead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Those finger prints on his throat were those of a woman,” said Dr. Stoughton. “They are much too small to have been inflicted by a man.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good Lord!” said Farley. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But they couldn’t have been inflicted by a woman,” observed Grimstead satirically, “because you said my story-was an hallucination. Beings that figure in hallucinations cannot commit red murders, can the &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Humph!” grunted Dr. Stoughton. Then, with a puzzled frown: “What do you think of all this, Grimstead?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is only one way to think.” replied the newspaperman. “Carey undoubtedly murdered his wife and came back to visit the scene of his crime, as murderers from time immemorial have done. His wife’s ghost was in tins room. I am as certain of that as I am that my name is Grimstead. It was Selma Carey’s fingers that reached from the grave and strangled her husband.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bosh!” ejaculated the physician. “Such things are impossible!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grimstead shrugged his shoulders. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing is impossible nowadays, Doctor,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/fingers-from-the-grave/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/fingers-from-the-grave/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Daughter of the Pigeon</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;i&quot;&gt;I&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last night in Marquesan waters, as Cleaves and I sat on the fore-deck of the anchored &lt;em&gt;Jezbel&lt;/em&gt;, listening to the talk of Leaping Fire, the Polynesian midshipman, the Bay of Traitors was lit with an eerie glow. Along Taha-uka, from the rockbound shore where the surf hurled its futile rage upon a Bastile of dun-colored stone, to the somnolent lights of Hivaoa dreaming beneath the black thunders of Temetiu, legions of phosphorus battled in green strife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… . “Yonder is the isle of Taoha, &lt;em&gt;Menikes&lt;/em&gt;” Leaping Fire was saying, pointing with his tattooed arm toward what seemed a mass of stone rising upon the moonlit night, his speech punctuated by the creaking of the boom as it swung with the slide and heave of the lazy rollers. “In the days before the Christian God came, when Po, the Power of Darkness, ruled the islands, the sea-robbers of Tahiti used to hide their treasures there—somewhere near the High Place and the Vale Where Dead Men Walk.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Vale Where Dead Men Walk,” r echoed. “What is that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A Valley below the High Place. From the sacrificial Altar of Po the old chiefs used to hurl their victims into the gorge;—in the days when the island was called Bloody Taoha …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a Polynesian always a Polynesian, and in the South Sea Islander there still lurks a desire for the taste of human flesh. ‘And I imagined that as he Spoke Leaping Fire could again hear, not without joy, the savage throbbing of rawhide drums in the dank, purple valleys of Bloody Taoha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is the island still inhabited ?” This from Cleaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. Years ago there were more than a thousand warriors on Taoha, but with the white man came plagues and wars—until now there are less than fifty. Mahatma. is the chief, but he is. slowly drinking himself to death with Kava. Ah, Menikes, the history of Taoha, the dying island is written in blood—and the future … But who knows the future ?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d like to visit the island,” observed Cleaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not go to Taoha,” warned Leaping Fire, “It is accursed. All die upon Taoha. And some say—” He paused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?” I urged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Some say that the spirits of the Tahitian pirates return from under the earth to guard their treasures …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleaves and I gazed seaward to the isle of tragic history, a bulk of stone that bared its nakedness to the low-hung tropic stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lay you two to one I can beat you swimming to the island, Rundel,” spoke up Cleaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smiled. “Take you up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is two miles away I” protested Leaping Fire. “And in the bay are mako and feke—fierce, man-devouring sharks and devil-fish I”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we would not listen to him; the tales of hidden loot and crimson deeds had stirred our blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m for the swim, sharks or no sharks,” said I, without bravado, for I did not realize the danger. “And as long as I’ve been in the tropics I have run across only one devil-fish. I’ll tell you, Cleaves, we’ll see who can reach the High Place first, you taking one end of the island and I the other, equalizing the distance. What do you say?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You do not know the way to—” began the Polynesian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Perhaps,” interposed Cleaves. “But you will tell us. Moreover, you and a couple of the crew will follow in a whale-boat and wait on the beach to bring us back. The race wilt be to the High Place and back to the whale-boat, the first one reaching the High Place piling several stones on the altar to let the other know he’s been there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was how it began. Down in the tropics men do queer things. The savage song of the surf on the coral reefs is a tune of lawlessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty minutes later Cleaves and I, stripped but for bathing trunks, were descending the gangway-stairs while Leaping Fire and others of the crew lowered a whale-boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I warned you, Menikes,” Leaping Fire called to us sadly from the deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I laughed—for his tales of piracy and the feel of the amorous wind on my body had aroused the sleeping boy within me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ready?” asked Cleaves— and I nodded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side by side we plunged into the green bay. The water was mildly cool— old wine to the muscles. When I returned to the surface I struck out toward the island, which seemed a mass of dark-ridden rocks beneath the fiery Southern Cross. Several yards away, the phosphorus leaping about him, was Cleaves, headed for the northern end of Taoha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That swim whipped the blood into every fiber and sinew of the being. Thinking little of sharks or devil-fish, I crossed the ruffled Bay of Traitors, and within an hour, a bit sore of thews 4 confess, I touched the sand on the southern end of the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarely have I seen such tropical beauty as on Taoha—cool white sands, strewn with sea-weed and curious shells; forests of mangoes, cocoanut-palms and bread-fruit; towering basalt rocks, honeycombed with caves and seeming riven with bronze as countless cascades and waterfalls caught the tarnished are-gent of the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the Polynesian’s instructions, I walked several rods down the beach and found the nearly obliterated trail that he had described, a path leading into a dark hollow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across valleys and ridges I sprinted, in the shadow of dripping rocks where the atmosphere was saturated with moisture, beneath feis-plants and the crimson-flowered huta-tree, not infrequently passing ruined paepaes, meager evidence of the gradual death of the little island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a trot of about a mile I gained the summit of a hill where red jasmine and orchids bloomed in profusion, and halted, breathless, looking upon what I knew to be the mist-laden Vale Where Dead Men Walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the stars seemed to hang lower, so low that the smell of them was in the atmosphere. Across the earth depression, stone ledges rose from the deep-sunken valley and the moonlight struck the bare rocks, transforming them from dead matter into living sheets of light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vale Where Dead Men Walk; well named; for a vague Something made me aware of its presence in the air by an imaginary, nevertheless ponderous, weight upon the lungs … as if the souls of the perished sea-robbers surged back upon the valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I slowly descended the ridge— slowly because of a strange reluctance to hurry—I had the uncanny feeling of one invading the dominion of the dead. Even the rank odors of the flowers suggested death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ascent of the ledges was not without difficulty; footholds were treacherous and more than once the roots of vines yielded to my weight, leaving me swinging at dizzy heights; but after ten minutes of breathless climbing, I dragged my full six feet over the edge of the High Altar and stood upright beside the Altar of Po.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidently Cleaves had not arrived. The decaying altar was bare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The High Place of Taoha crowned a gorge—a wound that gaped in the stomach of the earth like the heel-mark of a giant conqueror. At the bottom of a sheer drop of ten feet a narrow ledge clung to the stone walls, winding down into the orchid and fern-grown canon where the monster boulders threw their shadows across the rushing stream. On the side of the gorge opposite where I stood, a cave leered blackly from the rocks, and not far away was the lagoon, flanked with palm-fronds, a connecting link between river and sea. A mild roar insinuated itself upon the air —the combined booming of the gorge stream and the not distant surf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The savage, lawless splendor exerted over me an awesome spell and my imagination, ever eager to slip its leash, painted sinister figures in the gorge, ghostly shapes that materialized in the maw of the black cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of a sudden the blood began to throb through my head—for no conjuring of the fancy had created those forms; they were real, moving as phantoms upon the background of creepers that sprawled over the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dropped flat on my stomach, the touch of my skin upon the moist, cold stone sending a quick thrill trickling along my sensory nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figures, five in number, all lithe of body with the exception of one, crawled stealthily out of the gorge, and when they attained the top of the opposite side were swallowed by the breadfruit and cocoanut-palms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued to stare at the trees where they vanished. Men—islanders from the color of their naked skins—coming from the cave. It was rather intriguing, even insidious, and I immediately determined to penetrate the cave whose jaws had spewn them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I swung down from the High Place, dropping on the narrow ledge, I regretted my hasty action. ‘ The wiser plan would have been to wait for Cleaves, but I had started, without him, and being young, which is to say stubborn, too, I decided to finish it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than once during that perilous descent into the gorge did I wish I had abandoned my purpose on the narrow trail below the High Place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At length, a bit bruised and smarting from contact with the rocks, I found myself before the cave. Its mouth breathed damp, foul odors—the smell of fish and stale salt. A gradual incline went down into its throat, vanishing in somber darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt a queer dread of the place as I entered and before I had advanced many yards this aversion increased to terror. In the dank, foul air was an element that inspired in me a sensation similar to the one I had experienced as I crossed the Vale Where Dead Men Walk —the ponderous weight upon the chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered if by chance I was exploring a hiding place of the old Tahitian pirates, and if, in this gullet of darkness, I would stumble upon chests of loot—green with the rust and mold of ages. These thoughts, fanciful though they were, lured me on, drew me as in response to a magnet, deeper into the bowels of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could hear a distant booming—like the surf upon the rocks. Other than that, and a drip-drip-drip of water somewhere in the unseen cavity, it ached with the stillness of a sepulchre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After fully three minutes of groping forward my outstretched hands came into contact with a fungi-grown wall and as I turned to the left, my fingers slipping over the damp surface, I saw a broad strip of anœmic light streaking the darkness. It was very singular, such an illumination, apparently born of itself in the cavern, and I stood motionless, trying to discover its source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a noise that moved me—a groan—such as I once heard from the throat of a wounded devil-fish—a sound thrice hideous in the darksome cave. Had I coughed the following moment my heart would have lain upon the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the vague light the groan had come, causing me to take an involuntary step—and not in the direction of the streak of illumination. I wanted to bolt it, but instead I forced myself to wait for a repetition of the noise, and when a moment had passed in silence, emboldened by the hush, I moved toward the strange glow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reached it I almost laughed. In the ceiling of the cave was a gap of great depth and breadth that admitted the moonlight, thus creating the singular and startling pillar of light. Stars were visible, too—no longer 1ow-hung, but seeming at distances illimitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had almost forgotten the terrible groan in my discovery when it was repeated, weaker, nevertheless stirring the hair on my scalp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My eyes swept the shadows that hugged the pillar of light, and now, somewhat accustomed to the gloom, I could make out many square shapes beyond the glow—objects that I perceived to be nothing less than sea-chests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sight of them quickened my pulse. Iron-bound sea-chests; rusty locks; doubloons …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not reach the nearest chest quick enough and as my fingers found the lock they trembled violently. To my surprise the lid yielded—but not without a shrill of protest from the ancient hinges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to the next one. Following the shriek of the unoiled iron, sheer horror drove its rapier the length of my body. I drew back, terrified, yet fascinated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the huge sea-chest, face upturned,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ii&quot;&gt;II&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot adequately define my emotions. I was filled with a craven desire to run, to shut the lid upon the body, to do anything to escape the horrid cavern. How long I stood there, stiff with fright, I do not know, but it was some time, and the third groan aroused me from the fear-stupor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was alive, I told myself—probably injured. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forced myself to grip the figure and drag it from the sea-chest into the pallid moonlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a slim Marquesan youth, naked but for a pareu, an ugly blade driven hard into his stomach. The sight of the wound sickened me. His eyes were open and upon me—large, pathetic eyes. With him life was a matter of minutes. A surge of pity for the young body swept me. The death of youth is always a grim affair—a dark portal closing upon sublime vistas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise he smiled—a rather ghastly expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Menike,” he whispered, something dark upon his lips. “You, you help me … I—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go on,” I urged as his voice trailed off, and although I knew he was beyond the aid of man I added. “I will help you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again the ghastly smile. “Tahaiupehii—Daughter of the Pigeon—she—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I finally got the story, a tale of tears and flowers such as one would expect to hear on this dying island, told between gasps for breath:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His name was Red Moon. On Taoha was a maiden whom he desired for his wife—Tahaiupehii, Daughter of the Pigeon, pale of throat and dark of eyes. She was the child of Mahuma, the chief. Habuhamo, a chieftain of Fatu-hiva, also coveted the fair Tahaiupehii—and Habuhamo was fat and degenerate, and Daughter of the Pigeon despised him, for she, in turn, loved Red Moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this evening Red Moon had received a message to come to the Cave of the Laughing Lepers and as he entered he was attacked by Habuhamo and his men … stabbed. Before they put him in the sea-chest the obese Habuhamo told him that it was his intention to go to the paepae of Mahuma, the drinker of Kava, and steal the moon-throated Daughter of the Pigeon—after he had killed her father. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end he asked if I, the Menike, would follow Habuhamo and his men to the paepae of Mahuma and save Tahaiupehii. He was dying, he whispered, and if I did not go …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he finished his story he did a plucky thing—he withdrew the knife with a feeble wrench from his stomach, his tawny face convulsed with agony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You take knife,” he muttered, handing the bloody weapon to me, “You carry Red Moon on … back—and Red Moon show you paepae of Mahuma …” I did not believe the boy would last three minutes, but I lifted him as gently as I could and slung him on my back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I reached the High Place, after a tortuous ascent from the gorge with Red Moon clinging to my neck, I was disappointed. I had hoped that by good fortune I would meet my friend here, but instead of Cleaves I found a pile of stones upon the Altar of Po.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That journey from the Cave of the Laughing Lepers to the house of Mahuma is burned into my memory. After what seemed deathless aeons of plunging through jungles, a light glimmered among the trees. When Red Moon saw it he begged to be left here, saying he was an encumbrance now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Save her, Menike,” he pleaded piteously as I placed him on the round, death seeping into the liquid black eyes. “Tell her that …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I never knew what to tell her. From his lips came a sound like the flutter of beating wings… .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left him there, resolved to return later and bury him, and with the bloody knife that he had given me, I crept into the clearing around the thatched bamboo house. Lights shone from the door and one window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climbing upon the paepae, I crawled to the lighted window. It opened out from a small cool room with green mats and bamboo walls. The five Marquesas were there, wearing crimson pareus and necklaces of shark’s-teeth, all slim but one whom I knew to be Habuhamo. He was clad in a scarlet and yellow kahu-ropa, his big nose ringed with an ornament; fat and greasy in the light of the whale-oil lamp, with red, piglike eyes—a thing to loathe instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chief was speaking so swiftly in Marquesan that I, with only my smattering of the tongue, could not thoroughly understand him, and before I comprehended the full import of his words the four warriors filed out of the bamboo dwelling. I hardly bad the opportunity to drop in the shadows before they emerged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lay still, not daring to move or hardly breathe, until I heard their padded footsteps growing fainter, then I became bold enough to raise my eyes—just in time to see the last of the four vanish in the gloom of a path that deserted the clearing for the jungle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once more I peered within the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Habuhamo was seated Turk-fashion on the green mats, his back to ‘the doorway. I smiled with anticipation, for I hated him, not with the antagonism that is often the result of clashing personalities, but with a deep loathing as for some crawling thing of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gripping the blood-soiled knife I moved to the door and crept stealthily inside, halting a few feet behind Habuhamo. At that instant some psychic current conveyed to him the fact that he was not alone. He glanced over his shoulder and I looked straight into the narrow, piglike eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sound that issued from between his moist lips was like nothing human. He tried to make his feet, but I was upon him, one arm encircling his thick neck, the blade poised above his heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I ought to kill you instantly, Habuhamo,” I said in my bastard Marquesan, “but there is something I want to know before—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, no, don’t kill!” he whimpered in poor English, “I spik English—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where is Mahuma—and Tahaiupehii?” I demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Habuhamo’s red-shot eyes moved to a dark doorway on the left and I involuntarily loosened the grasp about his throat—and as I did he wrenched free, staggering to his feet with the scream of an angry boar. I scarcely had time to balance myself for the onslaught before the soft body was hurled upon me and his arms pressed me to his breast. I caught the reek of rum—and Habuhamo. ■ . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 struck with doubled fist instead of the knife—the left fist. It went home in the solar plexus, carrying my whole weight behind it, a foul blow I admit, and with that inhuman cry the island chief pitched forward like a sodden piece of driftwood upon the green mats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T stood above him, breathing hard and trying to clear my nostrils of the odor of him. He did not move. I turned his bulk over with my bare foot and the feel of it sickened me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That solar plexus blow had done him to unconsciousness. Habuhamo was out of it for at least fifteen minutes….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved into the adjoining room. Dark—but not so dark that I could not see the body on the floor. Instinct told me it was Mahuma. The wound was a nasty one—such as had been dealt Red Moon. Mahuma seemed so old, so helpless as he lay there in his own blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Daughter of the Pigeon—what of her?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dwelling boasted of three rooms and Tahaiupehii was in none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I quitted the room where Habuhamo lay upon the green mats, emerging upon the paepae, my eyes alighted upon the jungle trail that the islanders had taken. It was the only course left to pursue and I plunged between the whispering foliage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew the path led seaward, for I could hear the breakers and the pounding of the surf in the blow-holes, but I was not prepared for what I saw. The jungle dropped away before a ledge whose quartz-like surface scintillated in the moonlight. Several yards beyond the brush a narrow stream flung its torrents over spray-dashed rocks, tumbling headlong into a huge bowl of solid granite fully nineteen feet below, and here, still foaming furiously from the fall, it swirled between stone banks toward the sea. At the juncture where the river met rough water lofty cliffs overhung the beach, pierced with innumerable caves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself on the very verge of the cataract before I knew it. Below, on a flat rock at one side of the pool, was a form, slim and pale as a flame, the slender shoulders lost in masses of dark hair. Daughter of the Pigeon, I knew— for as she stood poised on the brink of the huge granite bowl she was as fair as that winged creature after which she was named. I could see that she wore a pareu twisted about her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not two yards behind her an islander was squirming over the spray-wet stone. Following him was another. On the opposite side of the pool the other Marquesans were crouched behind boulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unaware of her danger, Tahaiupehii stood on the edge of the rock, but even as I looked, her straight body flashed through the air, plunging into the foam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she vanished beneath the water one of the islanders crawled to the rim of the pool. An instant later her head appeared and she must have seen him, for a cry rang above the dull boom of the waterfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marquesan slipped into the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I experienced a moment of indecision; my brain strove to function quickly. The two figures were almost side by side in the current. Nineteen feet—a straight drop, and I did not know the depth. Yet …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gripped the blade between my teeth; took a deep breath. After that I was conscious of shooting through space … down … into what seemed a depthless pit. I struck the pool—went under with a force that lashed my flesh and expelled the air from my lungs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the battle against the torrent I almost lost the knife, but in some manner I managed to retain it. Through a whirling, opaque mass I came up, every inch of my body stinging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not more than a rod away I saw the two figures. I caught the gleam of grappling arms—saw a face that in the night was pale like blue moonlight, as exquisitely beautiful as any I have ever seen… .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a moment I reached them, closing about the shining dark neck, With the other hand I swung the knife. Together we sank. In that gray chaos we struggled, I slashing with the deadly blade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of a sudden it was conveyed to my brain, along with a strangling sensation, that my hand was holding nothing— that the knife-thrusts had told. I buoyed myself upward and attained the surface—alone. I doubt if the native ever came up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It must have been a rock that sent me out. At any rate the pain was sharp— in the back of the skull. Things went dim, I realized that a hand gripped my hair—then I knew … nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ill&quot;&gt;Ill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sleep that followed was not calm —nor can I hardly call it sleep, for during the whole period I had a peculiar awareness of things, of movement and a sound like unleashed thunder.. And with the advent of full consciousness I was not, as I expected, in the water, although it was damp and I could feel a cool spray upon my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat upright on cold stone, my head aching dreadfully. Something close at hand was roaring and in a hazy way I realized that the noise was responsible for the spray; but as my vision cleared I saw only dimness broken on one side by a glimmering sheet that was a shade lighter than the surrounding gloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gradually I comprehended. I was under the waterfall, in a dark recess in the rocks; the shifting curtain was nothing less than the cascading water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I was startled by a voice almost at my elbow, speaking in Marquesan— “Menike, you are awake—at last?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew her instantly, though she was little more than a blot in the dimness. Tahaiupehii—that exquisite young creature whose face I had seen momentarily as I fought the islander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am glad you have come back, Menike,” she said, creeping closer to me and slipping her small spray-wet hand in mine. Her nearness made me conscious of a pleasant odor—that of red jasmine. “Your head hit a rock—and ‘ I was afraid …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You saved me, Tahaiupehii?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I saw you as you dived from above —knew that you had done it to save me from Habuhamo’s men. After you were hurt I swam with you to this cave under the waterfall.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked about me. A grim, loathsome place. I imagined there were creeping things upon the rock floor. But it was sanctuary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You were very brave,” I commended, wondering how I was going to acquaint her with the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My vision was becoming better regulated now, and with the aid of the pale light that filtered through the liquid curtain I could see her tawny face. Daughter of the Pigeon—less than seventeen, I knew, a symphony of the world’s sorrow, a living symbol of that tragic isle to which she belonged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How did you happen here, Menike?” she questioned. “White men rarely come to Taoha any more. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I told her then—told her of my swim to the island and the discovery of Red Moon in the sea-chest in the Cave of the Laughing Lepers; told her of the death of her boy-lover near the paepae of Mahuma, and the finding of her father’s body in the bamboo room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man is ever crude in the presence of bereavement, and my words must have been dagger-thrusts. She wept … of course. Father and lover in a night. And as she sat there, drenched with spray, clad only in the dripping pareu, a tragically lovely figure, she recalled to me a field of lilies that I had once seen … just before the dawn, when the dew was upon ‘their chaste petals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be calm, O Tahaiupehii.” I enjoined gently, endeavoring to invest my sympathy in the words. “You are still in danger. Tell me, is anyone else aware of this cave?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I do not know, Menike.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If it is unknown to Habuhamo’s men they will think us drowned—but if it is known—they will come after us —or wait. …”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her small hand was still in mine and I felt her shudder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ah, I cannot stay here—in this darkness—thinking of Red Moon and my father! We must dive under the waterfall and swim for the sea!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubted the wisdom of such action and expressed my opinion, to which she replied: “We cannot discover if Habuhamo’s men are waiting by remaining here—and if they know of the cave and come after us—then the chances for escape will be less.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of Cleaves and the men— probably searching the island for me, and said, “My friends are somewhere on Taoha—and if we can make the sea —in the event Habuhamo’s men are waiting—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Only for your safety do I care,” she broke in. “You exposed yourself to danger for me, but I— All that I ever cared for is gone. Let another page of the history of this doomed island be written—in my blood—for rather than submit to Habuhamo I would kill myself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt a bit hysterical; I wanted to laugh. Such odds. Three islanders, probably searching the island for me, girl and me. It might have been rare sport had she not been there, but her presence gave the situation a horrid twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come, Menike.” I heard her say. “Let us go. This place stifles me—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It burned me to think of Habuhamo alive. I wished that I had used the knife upon his corrupt body… .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Very well, Tahaiupehii,” I agreed after a moment; “swim under water as far as you can—and stay ahead of me. I’ll attend to Habuhamo’s men.” I saw her smile—a fixed, lifeless expression. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart went cold within me as we swung down from the dripping rocks of the cavern. As the deluge showered her slim body I caught a glimpse of her face, paler than the whitest moons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That plunge was a horror to me. Bruised and breathless, my vision flecked with fire, I sank … down … into a reeling, watery world. My feet touched bottom before I was able to begin the fight upward, and when at last I gained the surface I dashed the spray from my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tahaiupehii was a yard or more ahead of me, arms agleam in the moonlight. They were there, the three islanders, sleek and sinister, slipping down from the bank of granite basin. There was a fourth, too, a fat, sprawling form high on the rocks. Habuhamo.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again I wished I had killed him in the bamboo hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The islanders were between Tahaiupehii and me, and Habuhamo was running along the shore parallel to the girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straight after the Marquesans I swam until I was abreast of the rear one. He was a wiry fellow, smaller than I, with an ugly blade gripped in his teeth. I struck him between the eyes and literally tore the knife from his mouth. As he sank I saw something black upon his lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that objects swam in a blur— blended water and rocks and over all the tranquil moon. Instead of launching an offensive against the other two natives, I succeeded in gaining a lead on them, and side by side Tahaiupehii and I were borne with the churning river. Occasionally I glanced behind at the pursuing islanders and that obese effigy on the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the deadliness of sharks the Marquesans followed—down with the boom and thunder of the stream into the mouth of the sea. Here the conflicting currents caught us in their turbulence and lashed us toward the giant rocks that fringed the shore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new peril loomed in the shape of the crags where the surf gave vent to its wrath, and we swam with all the strength we could assemble against the menace. Tahaiupehii was the first to reach the shore. I saw blood on her shoulder where the sea had flung her cruelly upon a jutting stone in her attempt to crawl from the surf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not far behind her, and as I staggered out of the thrashing water the bulky figure of Habuhamo appeared from behind the rocks of the river bank. Trapped. I threw the girl a look of futility. It was the finish, unless …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The cave!” I shouted, pressing the knife into her hand and pointing to a nearby cavity in the rugged cliffs. “Defend yourself until I come—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught the gleam of her pallid face as she obeyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Habuhamo must come first, I told myself—but Fate decided otherwise. Upon glancing back I perceived that one of the Marquesans had reached the shore and was clambering upon the rocks with a slim blade in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked about for some means of defense and my eyes dropped to the broken bits of boulders that lay at my feet. I bent and gripped one, lifted it above my head and let it fly. It struck him on the forehead with an ugly sound—like a crushed cocoanut shell… .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throwing a glance toward the cave I saw Tahaiupehii entering, Habuhamo at her heels. As I started to follow, a lean something from behind closed about my ankle—the hand of the last Marquesan, a terrible-looking fellow, naked and tattooed to a king’s delight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a bound he was upon me, and I let go my fist, sending him rolling among the rocks. Regaining my feet, I reached his side and bent over him. How I accomplished the following feat I do not know—but I grasped him by the nape of the neck and one limb and lifted him clawing above me; staggered to the edge of the surf and hurled him head-first into the shallow water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the weight left my hands I fell back on the rocks, but was up instantly —for the picture of Tahaiupehii as she darted into the cave, followed by that obese chief, was written in crimson on my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly I reached the mouth of the cave, a huge gap in the cliffs, only partially roofed and under almost two feet of water. From the rear came a muffled roar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splashing through water above my knees, often stumbling in the dimness, I covered what seemed miles, plunging with every step further into the cave. At an abrupt turn I was brought into an outlet that ran between lofty walls. The light of the yellow moon intruded upon the gloom, faintly revealing the sucking, snarling tide that rolled over the rocks and eddied between the cliffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were there—Tahaiupehii and Habuhamo, locked together on the surface of a boulder. As I rounded the corner I saw her thrust him away and down upon him, something glistening held over her heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shrieked—but the gnashing of the surf devoured my voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Habuhamo sprang—and at his first movement Tahaiupehii plunged the shining thing into her breast. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I closed my eyes; I think I reeled, too, so sick with horror was I, When I regained the mastery of myself I dashed through the water, which was now just below my armpits, and drew myself upon the boulder where Habuhamo stood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struck him from behind, knocked him flat upon the stone and threw myself upon him, pinning him beneath my weight and sending my doubled fist time after time into the bloated, horrid face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reason surrendered wholly to a frightful lust to murder. Blind to all except the bloodshot eyes beneath me, eyes that were glazed with horror, that beseeched mercy, I thrashed him, tore at his skin with my fingernails; choked him, beat his face until its grotesque mutilation forced a hysterical laugh from my throat. My own madness nauseated me, yet not once did I falter or weaken in the ghastly business—not until the body was lifeless, and with my bruised, bloody hands I pushed it to the edge of the boulder and kicked it into the delirious water. The last glimpse I had of that sodden, rum-soaked flesh called Habuhamo was as the surf flung its foaming arms about it and dragged it out to sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;IV&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TAHAIUPEHII was conscious when I knelt beside her on the edge—slim and white as fire, her wet dark hair spread in a tangle about her lovely face. More than ever her features seemed fashioned from blue moonlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tahaiupehii, Tahaiupehii!” I cried, trying to make myself heard above the surf. “I will take you out to my yacht —and you will get well—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daughter of the Pigeon smiled, not at me or what I said, but because, I believe, she heard another voice ringing clear above the tumult of the sea—the voice of her boy-lover in the darkness of Po.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She did not stir again, only lay there, lips locked, the childish smile frozen on her face. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I carried her down to the beach and placed her gently on the white sands. I shall never forget her as she lay there, her exquisite body dashed with the salt spray of the sea, the wound between her breasts as dark as a tropical gardenia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A half hour later Cleaves and Leaping Fire came upon us on the beach. They were about to abandon the search for me, believing me gone to the sharks. After I told them the story we carried Tahaiupehii to the paepae of her father, and here, not far from the bamboo house that had known her love and sorrow, we buried her… between Mahuma and Red Moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several hours afterward I was on the deck of the &lt;em&gt;Jezbel&lt;/em&gt;, and while a sullen, red-shot dawn flared above the thunders of Temetiu, the yacht throbbed out of the Bay of Traitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last sight that I had of Taoha, the dying isle, was through the morning fog, a haze that lay upon it like a spirit hand … as if the volcano that in ages past had spewn it above the green Pacific was reaching up from fathomless depths to reclaim it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O Tahaiupehii—paepae kaoka!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/daughter-of-the-pigeon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://talesofmurder.com/2014/07/09/daughter-of-the-pigeon/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
